<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Wind-Touched</name>
        <description>Wind-Touched from Humblewood Campaign Setting</description>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="background-wind-touched.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/humblewood-campaign-setting/backgrounds/background-wind-touched.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Wind-Touched" type="Background" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_BACKGROUND_WIND_TOUCHED">
		<description>
			<p></p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Acrobatics, Performance</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong>y ou can speak as well as understand Auran</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> a wind musical instrument (one of your choice), an ornate cloak, a symbol of the wind, common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</li>
            </ul>
            <h5>TITLE AND BLESSING</h5>
            <p>For some birdfolk, the moniker of Wind-Touched is merely a title, a symbol of their devotion to the wind and the natural world. Others have been told since birth that they were blessed by the wind, much in the way the Amaranthine Reya was in the old tales. Decide what your character believes, or roll on the table below to understand how they feel.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-10">d6</td><td>Acceptance</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>I am truly blessed and have power over the wind itself.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>I am devoted to the wind spirits, in action and title.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>I believe in nature and goodness.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>I will work tirelessly to earn the respect of those who give me this title.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>I accept this honor but have my doubts.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>I feel nothing for this title, and carry it against my will.</td></tr>
			</table>
            <div element="ID_HPP_HWCS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SUPERNATURAL_PRESENCE" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>The wind-touched are revered by believers and scrutinized by skeptics. For better or worse, they find themselves in a world of expectations they struggle to live up to.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Acrobatics, Performance, Musical Instrument, Auran</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Intrument (Wind-Touched)" supports="Musical Instrument" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_MM_LANGUAGE_AURAN"/>
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SUPERNATURAL_PRESENCE" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select name="Acceptance" type="List">
				<item id="1">I am truly blessed and have power over the wind itself.</item>
				<item id="2">I am devoted to the wind spirits, in action and title.</item>
				<item id="3">I believe in nature and goodness.</item>
				<item id="4">I will work tirelessly to earn the respect of those who give me this title.</item>
				<item id="5">I accept this honor but have my doubts.</item>
				<item id="6">I feel nothing for this title, and carry it against my will.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
				<item id="1">I never back down from a challenge.</item>
				<item id="2">I always end up being the center of attention.</item>
				<item id="3">I am gifted by the wind and destined for greatness.</item>
				<item id="4">I have no time for those who doubt me.</item>
				<item id="5">I seek out challenges to test myself.</item>
				<item id="6">I am better than everyone else.</item>
				<item id="7">I avoid showing my power at all costs.</item>
				<item id="8">I remain humble despite my blessing.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Ideal">
				<item id="1">Responsibility. The powers I have been gifted with are meant to serve the common good. (Good)</item>
				<item id="2">Heroism. The wind chose me to be a brave warrior and leader, so shall it be. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="3">Egotism. My powers situate me above others. The masses should know their place. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="4">Mysticism. Connected to nature, I speak for the wind and divine its will for others. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="5">Cynicism. What matters isn't whether or not my powers are genuine, but what advantages I can reap because of that belief. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="6">Naturalism. The wind speaks to my soul, and I am bound to go wherever it directs me. (Chaotic)</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Bond">
				<item id="1">I am guided by a wise elder who prepares me for my destiny.</item>
				<item id="2">I am estranged from my parents who don't believe in my blessing.</item>
				<item id="3">I seek to discredit the person who burdened me with this moniker.</item>
				<item id="4">I live in the shadow of my mentor, seeking their approval.</item>
				<item id="5">I have a sibling who is not blessed, which causes tension.</item>
				<item id="6">I am one with the wind. Personal relationships are fleeting.</item>
			</select>
			<select type="List" name="Flaw">
				<item id="1">I can't accept another's suggestion once I've set my path.</item>
				<item id="2">I expect nothing less than reverence from common people.</item>
				<item id="3">I blindly trust in the power of my blessing.</item>
				<item id="4">I am overly concerned about how others see me.</item>
				<item id="5">I will prove my worth, even if it means putting myself and my friends in danger.</item>
				<item id="6">I am burdened with responsibility, and find it hard to make even the simplest decisions.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Feature: Supernatural Presence" type="Background Feature" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SUPERNATURAL_PRESENCE">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Whether or not you are truly Wind-Touched, there are folk all across Everden that believe that you have been divinely blessed. If you make a show of power or skill that can be attributed to the wind or air, such as feats of acrobatics or commanding unseen forces, those believers will be bolstered by your supernatural presence. They will support you and, depending on how well you have convinced them of your powers, treat you with reverence and possibly even worship.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Supernatural Presence" />
	</element>
</elements>