<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Shadow Gnawer</name>
		<description>Shadow Gnawer from Book of Ebon Tides</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="barbarian-shadow-gnawer.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/book-of-ebon-tides/archetypes/barbarian-shadow-gnawer.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Shadow Gnawer" type="Archetype" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_BARBARIAN_SHADOW_GNAWER">
		<supports>Primal Path</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Dark energy infuses the Shadow Realm, corrupting and corroding everything it touches. Some barbarians intentionally consume this raw shadow, infusing their bodies with shadow energy to manifest potent magical abilities.</p>
			<p class="indent">Many of the barbarians who walk this path do so to absorb harmful shadow magic into themselves in order to protect others from its influence. A smaller group consumes shadow simply because they cannot resist its ever-present temptation.</p>
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_SHADOW_SMOKE" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CREEPING_FOG" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CONSUME_DARKNESS" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CORROSIVE_HAZE" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_SHADOW_SMOKE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CREEPING_FOG" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CONSUME_DARKNESS" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CORROSIVE_HAZE" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shadow Smoke" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_SHADOW_SMOKE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, you emanate tendrils of shadow smoke while you rage. The smoke extends 10 feet from you in every direction. Any creature (other than you) that starts its turn in the smoke has disadvantage on its next attack roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Rage">
			<description>You emanate tendrils of shadow smoke while you rage. The smoke extends 10 feet from you in every direction. Any creature (other than you) that starts its turn in the smoke has disadvantage on its next attack roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Creeping Fog" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CREEPING_FOG">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, you can burst into a mist of raw shadow and then reassemble yourself somewhere else. As an action, you magically teleport, along with any equipment you are wearing or carrying, up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. Before or after teleporting, you can make one melee attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You magically teleport, along with any equipment you are wearing or carrying, up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. Before or after teleporting, you can make one melee attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Consume Darkness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CONSUME_DARKNESS">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, while raging, you can feed on the shadows around you to restore your vitality. While in dim light or darkness, you can use a bonus action to regain hit points equal to 1d12 + your Constitution modifier. For the duration of your rage (up to 1 minute), you regain 1 hit point at the start of each of your turns.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>While raging in dim light or darkness, you can regain hp equal to 1d12 + {{constitution:modifier}}. For the duration of your rage, you regain 1 hp at the start of each of your turns.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Corrosive Haze" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHADOW_GNAWER_CORROSIVE_HAZE">
		<description>
			<p>At 14th level, your Shadow Smoke is more potent. Any hostile creature that enters the smoke or starts its turn in the smoke must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the beginning of its next turn. The DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier. Creatures that don't rely on eyesight are immune to this effect.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Shadow Smoke">
			<description>ny hostile creature that enters the smoke or starts its turn in the smoke must succeed on a Constitution saving throw (DC {{boet:shadow gnawer:corrosive haze:dc}}) or be blinded until the beginning of its next turn. Creatures that don't rely on eyesight are immune to this effect.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="boet:shadow gnawer:corrosive haze:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="boet:shadow gnawer:corrosive haze:dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="boet:shadow gnawer:corrosive haze:dc" value="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
</elements>
