<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Umbral Binder</name>
		<description>Umbral Binder from Book of Ebon Tides</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="rogue-umbral-binder.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/book-of-ebon-tides/archetypes/rogue-umbral-binder.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Umbral Binder" type="Archetype" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_UMBRAL_BINDER">
		<supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Some rogues are content to steal mere treasures, but umbral binders possess the energies that shape the world. Through secret rites and rituals, these rogues have learned to bind the powers of shadow into themselves and to use its power to fuel their abilities.</p>
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_EYES_IN_THE_DARK" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_SHADOW_BIND" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_CLOAKED_DAGGER" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_BLACK_MAGIC" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_SHADOW_GRASP" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_EYES_IN_THE_DARK" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_SHADOW_BIND" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_CLOAKED_DAGGER" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_BLACK_MAGIC" level="13" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_SHADOW_GRASP" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Eyes in the Dark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_EYES_IN_THE_DARK">
		<description>
			<p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your experience with the raw magic of shadow affects your senses. You gain darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<stat name="darkvision:range" value="120" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shadow Bind" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_SHADOW_BIND">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 3rd level, you can perform a special ritual to siphon the power of shadow and bind it to yourself. You can conduct this ritual during a long rest. Performing the ritual requires time spent meditating in nonmagical darkness for at least 1 hour. At the end of the ritual, you choose one of the following effects, which lasts for 24 hours or until you perform the ritual again:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When you are in dim light or darkness, as part of your move, you can teleport up to half your speed to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness. You then have advantage on the first Dexterity (Stealth) check you make before the end of your turn.</li>
				<li>When you are in dim light or darkness, if you move at least half your speed, you benefit from a perpetual half cover until the start of your next turn: +2 bonus to AC and Dexterity saving throws.</li>
				<li>When you hit with a melee or ranged weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal additional cold damage equal to your proficiency bonus. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can perform a special ritual during a long rest. Performing the ritual requires time spent meditating in nonmagical darkness for at least 1 hour. At the end of the ritual, you choose one of the following effects, which lasts for 24 hours or until you perform the ritual again: &#13;
			• When you are in dim light or darkness, as part of your move, you can teleport up to half your speed to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness. You then have advantage on the first Dexterity (Stealth) check you make before the end of your turn. &#13;
			• When you are in dim light or darkness, if you move at least half your speed, you benefit from a perpetual half cover until the start of your next turn: +2 bonus to AC and Dexterity saving throws. &#13;
			• When you hit with a melee or ranged weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an additional {{proficiency}} cold damage. (1/Turn).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Cloaked Dagger" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_CLOAKED_DAGGER">
		<description>
			<p>At 9th level, shadows hide your every strike. You gain an additional way to use your Sneak Attack. You don't need advantage on the attack roll to use your Sneak Attack against a creature if you are within 30 feet, are in dim light or darkness, and you don't have disadvantage on the attack roll. All the other rules for Sneak Attack still apply to you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You don't need advantage on the attack roll to use your Sneak Attack against a creature if you are within 30 ft, are in dim light or darkness, and you don't have disadvantage on the attack roll. All the other rules for Sneak Attack still apply to you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Black Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_BLACK_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p>At 13th level, you can draw more power from the shadows bound to you. As a bonus action, you can cast <i>darkness</i> without providing material components. Once you use this feature three times, you cannot do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As a bonus action, you can cast <i>darkness</i> without providing material components. (3/Long Rest). &#13;
			Additionally, when you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shadow Grasp" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_UMBRAL_BINDER_SHADOW_GRASP">
		<description>
			<p>At 17th level, you can wrap your foes in debilitating shadow. When you deal Sneak Attack damage to a creature, you can force them to make a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier). If the save fails, the target is restrained for 1 minute. The restrained target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>When you deal Sneak Attack damage to a creature, you can force them to make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{boet:umbral binder:shadow grasp:dc}}). If the save fails, the target is restrained for 1 minute. The restrained target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="boet:umbral binder:shadow grasp:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="boet:umbral binder:shadow grasp:dc" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="boet:umbral binder:shadow grasp:dc" value="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
</elements>
