<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Mother of Sorrows</name>
		<description>Mother of Sorrows from Book of Ebon Tides</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="warlock-mother-of-sorrows.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/book-of-ebon-tides/archetypes/warlock-mother-of-sorrows.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Mother of Sorrows" type="Archetype" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS">
		<supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Universal suffering has given rise to an enigmatic being known as the Mother of Sorrows, and warlocks who bind themselves to her cause seek to spread her poisonous vengeance. The Mother of Sorrows was born from the suffering of parents who have lost children to pestilence, disease, and treachery, and her gifts grant warlocks the power to avenge the thousands of sorrows laid at her feet.</p>
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_POISON_SOUL" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_VENOMOUS_MARK" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_SICKENING_REVENGE" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_DARK_INOCULATION" />
			<div element="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_TOUCH_OF_SORROW" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_POISON_SOUL" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_VENOMOUS_MARK" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_SICKENING_REVENGE" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_DARK_INOCULATION" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_TOUCH_OF_SORROW" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
		<description>
			<p>The Mother of Sorrows lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Expanded Spell List</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>detect poison and disease, inflict wounds</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>ray of enfeeblement, silence</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>stinking cloud, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>4th</td><td><em>greater invisibility, phantasmal killer</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>cloudkill, contagion</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_POISON_AND_DISEASE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_STINKING_CLOUD</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_INVISIBILITY</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_KILLER</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL</extend>
			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTAGION</extend>
		</spellcasting>
	</element>

	<element name="Poison Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_POISON_SOUL">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 1st level, your affinity for poison becomes supernatural. Any poison damage you deal ignores any resistance or immunity.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Any poison damage you deal ignores any resistance or immunity.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Venomous Mark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_VENOMOUS_MARK">
		<description>
			<p>Also at 1st level, as a bonus action, choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The target is cursed for 1 minute. The curse ends early if the target dies, you die, or you are incapacitated. Until the curse ends, you deal an extra 1d6 poison damage to the target whenever you hit it with a spell attack. (You can only apply this damage once per spell even if there are multiple spell attack instances, such as with eldritch blast.)</p>
			<p class="indent">If the target drops to 0 hit points before the curse ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to curse a new creature. Only one creature can be affected with a venomous mark at any given time.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>Choose one creature you can see within 30 ft of you. The target is cursed for 1 minute. The curse ends early if the target dies, you die, or you are incapacitated. Until the curse ends, you deal an extra 1d6 poison damage to the target whenever you hit it with a spell attack. (You can only apply this damage once per spell even if there are multiple spell attack instances, such as with eldritch blast.)
			If the target drops to 0 hp before the curse ends, you can use a bonus action on a subsequent turn of yours to curse a new creature. Only one creature can be affected with a venomous mark at any given time.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Sickening Revenge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_SICKENING_REVENGE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, you can take vengeance on those who harm you. When you take damage, you can use your reaction to attempt to poison the creature that damaged you. The triggering creature must make a Constitution saving throw against your warlock spell save DC or become poisoned for 1 minute. An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the condition on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>When you take damage, you can use your reaction to attempt to poison the creature that damaged you. The triggering creature must make a Constitution saving throw (DC {{warlock:spellcasting:dc}}). An affected creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the condition on a success.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Dark Inoculation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_DARK_INOCULATION">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 10th level, your poisonous magic has infused your body. You are immune to disease, poison damage, and the poisoned condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are immune to disease and the poisoned condition.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Touch of Sorrow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Book of Ebon Tides" id="ID_KBP_BOET_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MOTHER_OF_SORROWS_TOUCH_OF_SORROW">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 14th level, when you hit a creature with an attack, you can use this feature to infuse the target with your sorrow. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw or be paralyzed and poisoned for 24 hours. The creature remains paralyzed until it takes damage or is no longer poisoned.</p>
			<p class="indent">You must finish a short or long rest before you can use this feature again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>When you hit a creature with an attack, you can use this feature to infuse the target with your sorrow. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw or be paralyzed and poisoned for 24 hours. The creature remains paralyzed until it takes damage or is no longer poisoned.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
</elements>
