<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Shadow Stalker</name>
		<description>Shadow Stalker from Cthulhu by Torchlight</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="rogue-shadowstalker.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/cthulhu-by-torchlight/archetypes/rogue-shadowstalker.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Shadow Stalker" type="Archetype" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER">
		<supports>Rogue Subclass</supports>
		<description>
			<div class="sidebar">
				<p class="flavor">“Some folk keep to the shadows. I bring them with me wherever I go.”</p>
				<p class="text-align:right">— Kulden</p>
			</div>
			<p>Rogues are at home in the shadows, slipping into the darkness to evade their enemies, strike down unsuspecting foes, or carry off great treasures. Some Rogues feel a strange presence when they slip into the darkness, whispers at the edge of their hearing.</p>
			<p class="indent">These Rogues hear the call of the shadow, and they are fated to become bound. The darkness can sense a void in a creature's heart, a yearning that can never be filled. Or perhaps it can. The shadows reach out with a simple offer: yield something of your past and open a path to a future where your empty heart is filled. Those who hear this offer are doomed to accept it, and they are doomed to regret it. Yet, the shadow chooses its partners carefully, knowing that those marked for its bargain can't resist.</p>
			<div element="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOWY_REFLECTION" />
			<div element="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES" />
			<div element="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOWED_SUCCOR" />
			<div element="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_GATE" />
			<div element="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_TRUE_SHADOW" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOWY_REFLECTION" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOWED_SUCCOR" level="9"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_GATE" level="13"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_TRUE_SHADOW" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 3: Shadowy Reflection" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOWY_REFLECTION">
		<description>
			<p>As a Magic action, you expel your shadow from your side and command its actions. It appears in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you and is your size. The Shadowy Reflection can manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an unattended item, or pour out a vial. As a Magic action on your later turns or as part of the Bonus Action when you use your Cunning Action feature, you can control your shadow again. You can move your shadow up to your Speed. The shadow can't attack, active magic items, or carry more than 10 pounds. Your shadow disappears when it takes any damage, is the target of any effect, or if you have the Incapacitated condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Shadowy Reflection" action="Action">
			<description>You expel your shadow from your side and command its actions. It appears in an unoccupied space within 5 ft of you and is your size. The Shadowy Reflection can manipulate an object, open an unlocked door or container, stow or retrieve an unattended item, or pour out a vial. As an Action on your later turns or as part of the Bonus Action when you use your Cunning Action feature, you can control your shadow again. You can move your shadow up to {{speed}} ft. The shadow can't attack, active magic items, or carry more than 10 lbs. Your shadow disappears when it takes any damage, is the target of any effect, or if you have the Incapacitated condition.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 3: Shadow Motes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES">
		<description>
			<p>You have the power to control shadows, which is represented by your Shadow Motes. You can expend these motes to enhance or fuel certain Shadow Stalker features. You have an amount of motes equal to your Rogue level. You start knowing three such features: Shadow Scout, Shadow Swap, and Vexing Shadow, each of which is detailed below. When you expend a Shadow Mote, it is unavailable until you finish a Long Rest, at the end of which you regain all your expended motes. You also regain 1 expended Shadow Mote when you reduce a Hostile creature to 0 Hit Points.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em><strong>Shadow Scout.</strong></em> As a Magic action, you can expend 1 Shadow Mote to project your senses through your Shadowy Reflection. For 1 minute, you can see and hear through it as if you were located where it is, and you can move it up to 120 feet away from you. This effect ends early if you take any damage or if you have the Incapacitated condition.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em><strong>Shadow Swap.</strong></em> When you use your Cunning Action feature, as part of that Bonus Action, you can expend 1 Shadow Mote to swap places with your Shadowy Reflection. You teleport to its space, and it teleports to your space. If you appear in an occupied space, you are shunted to the nearest unoccupied space and take Force damage equal to the number of feet you are moved.</p>
			<p class="indent"><em><strong>Vexing Shadow.</strong></em> Immediately after you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon and your Shadowy Reflection is within 5 feet of that creature, you can expend 1 Shadow Mote to gain the Invisible condition against that creature until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Shadow Motes" usage="{{level:rogue}}/Long Rest">
			<description>You have {{level:rogue}} Shadow Motes. When you expend a Shadow Mote, it is unavailable until you finish a Long Rest, at the end of which you regain all your expended motes. You also regain 1 expended Shadow Mote when you reduce a Hostile creature to 0 HPs.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES_SHADOW_SCOUT" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES_SHADOW_SWAP" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES_VEXING_SHADOW" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Scout" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES_SHADOW_SCOUT">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>As a Magic action, you can expend 1 Shadow Mote to project your senses through your Shadowy Reflection. For 1 minute, you can see and hear through it as if you were located where it is, and you can move it up to 120 feet away from you. This effect ends early if you take any damage or if you have the Incapacitated condition.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Shadow Mote">
			<description>You can project your senses through your Shadowy Reflection. For 1 minute, you can see and hear through it as if you were located where it is, and you can move it up to 120 ft away from you. This effect ends early if you take any damage or if you have the Incapacitated condition.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Shadow Swap" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES_SHADOW_SWAP">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you use your Cunning Action feature, as part of that Bonus Action, you can expend 1 Shadow Mote to swap places with your Shadowy Reflection. You teleport to its space, and it teleports to your space. If you appear in an occupied space, you are shunted to the nearest unoccupied space and take Force damage equal to the number of feet you are moved.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Shadow Mote">
			<description>When you use your Cunning Action feature, as part of that Bonus Action, you can swap places with your Shadowy Reflection. You teleport to its space, and it teleports to your space. If you appear in an occupied space, you are shunted to the nearest unoccupied space and take Force damage equal to the number of feet you are moved.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Vexing Shadow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_MOTES_VEXING_SHADOW">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Immediately after you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon and your Shadowy Reflection is within 5 feet of that creature, you can expend 1 Shadow Mote to gain the Invisible condition against that creature until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Shadow Mote">
			<description>Immediately after you hit a creature with an attack roll using a weapon and your Shadowy Reflection is within 5 ft of that creature, you can gain the Invisible condition against that creature until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 9: Shadowed Succor" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOWED_SUCCOR">
		<description>
			<p>You can weave shadows to intercept an attack and direct it harmlessly into a void of darkness. When you use your Uncanny Dodge feature, you can reduce the attack's damage against you to 0.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Shadowed Succor" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you use your Uncanny Dodge feature, you can reduce the attack's damage against you to 0.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 13: Shadow Gate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_SHADOW_GATE">
		<description>
			<p>Your Shadowy Reflection can create an umbral pathway that you and your companions can use. As a Bonus Action while your Shadowy Reflection is within 5 feet of you, you can expend 4 Shadow Motes to cast <i>Dimension Door</i>. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it. Your Shadowy Reflection can travel through the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Shadow Gate" action="Bonus Action" usage="4 Shadow Motes">
			<description>While your Shadowy Reflection is within 5 ft of you, you can expend 4 Shadow Motes to cast Dimension Door. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it. Your Shadowy Reflection can travel through the spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 17: True Shadow" type="Archetype Feature" source="Cthulhu by Torchlight" id="ID_CSM_CBT_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_SHADOW_STALKER_TRUE_SHADOW">
		<description>
			<p>Your Shadowy Reflection gains the ability to become a deadly clone of you. As a Bonus Action, your Shadowy Reflection transforms into an exact duplicate of you.</p>
			<p class="indent">For 1 hour, your Shadowy Reflection becomes substantial, and you can have it take the Attack, Hide, or Utilize action by controlling it with your Shadowy Reflection feature. Its Attack action uses your game statistics, including class features, feats, and weapons. It vanishes when reduced to 0 Hit Points.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you make an attack roll against a creature within 5 feet of the duplicate, the attack roll has Advantage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="True Shadow" action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>Your Shadowy Reflection transforms into an exact duplicate of you. For 1 hour, your Shadowy Reflection becomes substantial, and you can have it take the Attack, Hide, or Utilize action by controlling it with your Shadowy Reflection feature. Its Attack action uses your game statistics, including class features, feats, and weapons. It vanishes when reduced to 0 HPs. When you make an attack roll against a creature within 5 ft of the duplicate, the attack roll has Advantage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
</elements>
