<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Spells</name>
		<description>Spells from Humblewood Campaign Setting</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/humblewood-campaign-setting/spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Ambush Prey" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_AMBUSH_PREY">
		<supports>Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You channel primal predatory energies to perfectly conceal your presence in order to surprise your target. You become invisible for the spell's duration, granting advantage on all Dexterity (Stealth) checks to remain hidden. The invisibility will last for the duration of the spell, however, moving 5 feet or more from your position when you cast the spell will end the effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">As long as you remain invisible, the first attack you make against any target who is unaware of your presence deals an additional 1d6 points of damage. This attack ends the spell.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot above 2nd level, the damage of your first attack increases by 1d6 for every slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a broken twig</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Elevated Sight" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_ELEVATED_SIGHT">
		<supports>Cleric, Druid, Ranger, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cast your eyes skyward, granting you sight from a higher vantage point. You project your vision to see through an invisible sensor which appears in a spot up to 120 feet above you. You can see through the sensor as if you were flying, granting a full 360 degree view from its location.</p>
			<p class="indent">The sensor moves with you, retaining its height in relation to you. You can use a bonus action to adjust the sensor's height, but only to a maximum of 120 feet above you.</p>
			<p class="indent">While looking through this sensor you are blind, though you can switch between seeing through the sensor or through your own eyes at any time during your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Feathered Reach" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_FEATHERED_REACH">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You transform your arms into powerful wings, and your fingers into long, graceful feathers. The effects of this spell last 1 minute, at which point the feathers gradually fall out, causing you to float gently to the ground as your arms return to their original form. This spell confers a number of benefits upon the caster:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>As a bonus action, you can fly up to double your movement speed. You must land once you finish your movement, although you do not take fall damage while this spell is active, as your feathered arms bear you gently to the ground.</li>
				<li>You can use your powerful feathered arms to propel yourself upward a distance equal to half your movement speed. You can do this once during your turn and may use it in conjunction with a regular jump.</li>
				<li>When falling, you can use your reaction to stiffen your arms, and glide on the wind. You may fly up to your movement speed, in any direction, choosing where you land.</li>
				<li>You gain advantage on all Athletics checks used to make a long or high jump. You do not need to move 10 feet before you jump to gain distance, and you triple the distance you would jump normally.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">In order to benefit from this spell your hands must be free of shields and heavy weapons, and you cannot be encumbered.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small feather</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Globe of Twilight" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_GLOBE_OF_TWILIGHT">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You shroud the area surrounding you in a sphere of night sky, dotted with miniature stars. The twilight conceals your allies, but clearly illuminates your enemies.</p>
			<p class="indent">The area affected by this spell is lightly obscured by magical shadow, within which small constellations softly twinkle. Aside from these stars, only light produced by a spell of 3rd level or higher can properly illuminate any area inside the sphere. Nonmagical light does not function inside the sphere, and all other forms of magical radiance can only produce dim light in a 5-foot space.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you cast this spell you may designate any number of creatures you can see to be concealed by the supernatural shadows while in the sphere. A concealed creature has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks when inside the sphere and may attempt to hide at any time. Because the area of the spell is lightly obscured, creatures within the spell's area have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks made to see those outside of it.</p>
			<p class="indent">All other creatures in the area are dazzled by the light of the miniature stars, causing them to have disadvantage on all perception checks inside the sphere. When such a creature enters the spell's area for the first time, or starts its turn there, it must make a Wisdom saving throw or be blinded until the end of its turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (15-foot radius)</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a dab of pitch and a bag of glittering sand</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Gust Barrier" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_GUST_BARRIER">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You spread your arms wide, allowing yourself to become enveloped by the air around you. Until the end of your next turn, any ranged attack against you is made with disadvantage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Melee attackers who successfully hit you must make a Constitution saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the attacker is flung away from you up to 10 feet and is knocked prone.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Invoke the Amaranthine" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_INVOKE_THE_AMARANTHINE">
		<supports>Cleric, Paladin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call upon the power of an Amaranthine to grant yourself insight into the Great Rhythm that moves all things. When you cast this spell, roll two d20s, and record what you rolled. For each die, choose either attack roll, skill check, or saving throw. You can choose each option multiple times. For the next 24 hours, you may substitute any roll of an ally or enemy you can see within 60 feet with one of the recorded numbers that matches the type of roll you wish to replace (attack roll, skill check, or saving throw). The target still adds any relevant modifiers to this number, but otherwise treat the substituted number as the number they rolled.</p>
			<p class="indent">To do this, you must spend a reaction to present your holy symbol and invoke the name of the Amaranthine whose energies you called upon. You can do this anytime after the skill check, saving throw or attack has been rolled, but before the outcome of the event has been determined. The spell ends after 24 hours have passed, or when both dice have been expended.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a holy symbol of the Amaranthine</set>
			<set name="duration">24 hours</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Shape Plants" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_SHAPE_PLANTS">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You call upon gentle natural magics to alter the growth of plants. Any plant life you can see within range that fits within a 5-foot cube can take on whatever shape you desire. Additionally, if the plant is a bramble or capable of growing thorns, you may turn the affected area into difficult terrain, causing 2d4 points of piercing damage for every 5 feet moved through the area you shaped. You may also increase or decrease the number of flowers, vines, leaves, thorns, branches, or fruits produced by any plant you shape.</p>
			<p class="indent">After one hour, the magic of your spell fades, and the plant resumes its normal shape. If you can use speak with plants (or a similar ability) to communicate with the plant, you may persuade it to retain its new form. Different plants have different feelings and attitudes, and if the form is too different from its natural shape it is likely to decline. If the plant accepts, at the GM's discretion, it will retain the form you have sculpted it into, in which case the effect becomes permanent.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot above 4th level, the size of the cube of plant life you can affect with the spell increases by an additional 5 feet for every slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">piercing</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Spiny Shield" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_SPINY_SHIELD">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An ethereal barrier of spikes, made of magical force, interposes itself between you and an attacker. Until your next turn, when you are hit by a melee attack, the barrier reduces the damage you are dealt by 2d4, and deals the same amount of piercing damage to the attacker. The shield is ineffective against ranged attackers, but still provides a +2 bonus to AC (treat as half cover) against them for the duration.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot above 1st level, increase the spell's effect by an additional 1d4 for every slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Reaction</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small quill</set>
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Stellar Bodies" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_STELLAR_BODIES">
		<supports>Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Attack, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create two small stars that orbit you. They twinkle pleasantly, shedding dim light in a 10-foot radius centered on you. The stars protect you. If a creature within 5 feet of you hits you with a melee attack they must make a Wisdom saving throw or take 1d8 points of radiant damage for each star orbiting you.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once per round, on your turn, you may use your action to cause a star to streak towards an enemy, expending it as it explodes in a blinding flash. Make a ranged spell attack against an enemy within 120 feet, dealing 4d8 points of radiant damage on a hit. The target must then make a Constitution saving throw or be blinded until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell ends when either its duration expires, you fall unconscious, or you have expended all of your stars.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot above 4th level, you may create one additional star for every two slot levels above 4th. For each additional star orbiting you, the radius of dim light centered on you increases by 5 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">radiant</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Special</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Veil of Dusk" type="Spell" source="Humblewood Campaign Setting" id="ID_HPP_HWCS_SPELL_VEIL_OF_DUSK">
		<supports>Druid, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You incant towards a creature, cloaking them in a shadowy veil of darkness and silence. The target gains a +1 bonus to their armor class and makes Stealth checks with advantage for the duration of the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of soot</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>
