<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Spells</name>
		<description>Spells from Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="spells.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/obojima-tales-from-the-tall-grass/spells.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Armament" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_ARMAMENT">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Paladin, Ranger, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Up to five simple or martial weapons of your choice materialize in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The weapons are nonmagical, but they are well-made and stylistically look however you would like. The weapons vanish when the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can summon three additional simple or martial weapons of your choice for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">metal powder</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="At Your Side" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_AT_YOUR_SIDE">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Ranger, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You and up to three other willing creatures of your choice within range form an arcane bond, which magically pulls you forward when moving towards each other. For the duration, each target's speed increases by 5 feet, and whenever an affected creature ends its turn, other targets of the spell can use their reaction to move up to half their speed in the direction of another affected creature.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 hours</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Beast Transmutation" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_BEAST_TRANSMUTATION">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell transforms a beast that you can see within range into a new humanoid form. An unwilling creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw to avoid the effect. The spell has no effect on a beast with 0 hit points.</p>
			<p class="indent">The transformation lasts for the duration, or until the target drops to 0 hit points or dies. The new form has the appearance of a humanoid of any race you choose. The target's game statistics, excluding mental ability scores, are replaced by the statistics of a commoner. It retains its alignment and personality.</p>
			<p class="indent">The target assumes the hit points of its commoner form. When it reverts to its normal form, the beast returns to the number of hit points it had before it transformed. If it reverts as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to its normal form. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce the beast's normal form to 0 hit points, it isn't knocked unconscious.</p>
			<p class="indent">The creature is limited in the actions it can perform by the nature of its new form.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the spell's duration increases by 1 hour for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Bubble Lift" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_BUBBLE_LIFT">
		<supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You blow a bubble around any solid, granular, or liquid object that weighs 500 pounds or less, causing it to float 4 feet off the ground. No matter what the contents of the bubble are, the bubble weighs 10 pounds and can be pushed using an action. Strong winds or effects that would push a creature also push the bubble. The bubble always floats at least 4 feet off the ground, and descends from a fall at a speed of 10 feet per round.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, a creature can pierce the outside of the bubble, causing it to pop and releasing its contents.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can increase the weight the bubble can lift by 500 pounds for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Butterfly Storm" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_BUTTERFLY_STORM">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a chaotic cloud of butterflies in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range. The area is heavily obscured, and resting smoke or fog in the area is dispersed.</p>
			<p class="indent">Creatures of your choice in the area when you cast this spell ignore the following effects. For the duration, the affected area is difficult terrain. When a creature attempts to leave the spell's area, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it is pulled back to an unoccupied space closest to the center of the sphere.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">insect legs</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Conjure Ocean" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_CONJURE_OCEAN">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You teleport a random 20-foot cube of water from the bottom of the ocean to an area that you can see within range. The water holds its cube shape as if held within a container. A creature can enter and exit the water as it normally would.</p>
			<p class="indent">When the spell ends, the water loses its shape, crashing to the ground and spreading outward. Any creature inside the water at this time is carried 30 feet in a random direction.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a piece of witch's eye coral</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Control Animal" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_CONTROL_ANIMAL">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose a beast that you can see within range. The beast is affected if it has a challenge rating of 2 or lower; otherwise, the spell fails. An affected creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw, or you take total and precise control of it, as your consciousness enters its body. While under the effect of this spell, you can see through the creature's eyes and hear what it hears, gaining the benefits of any special senses that the creature has. You can move and take actions as the creature and can perform tasks the creature could feasibly perform. During this time, your body is considered unconscious; this doesn't affect your ability to concentrate on this spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the creature takes damage, you must make a Wisdom (Animal Handling) check, with a DC equal to 10 or half the damage it took, whichever number is higher. On a failure, the creature regains control of its body, and the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can increase the weight the bubble can lift by 500 pounds for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a bit of matted fur</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Counterspy" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_COUNTERSPY">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create an intricate arcane circle made of candles and sand centered on a point on the ground within range. The circle can have a radius of 10 feet or less. If at any point before the spell ends a creature outside the circle can see or hear you through magical or nonmagical means, the candle's flames will change color. If a spell or magical effect was used, you are aware of it and understand the extent of its effects.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">5 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a bag of sand and six candles</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Create Spirit Train Stop" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_CREATE_SPIRIT_TRAIN_STOP">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As you cast the spell, you inscribe onto your blank ticket the code of a permanent train stop of your choice whose stop number you're already familiar with. A shimmering sign and small bench appears behind you as the Wandering Line arrives on tracks which materialize before it. Your ticket allows passage for you and up to eight creatures of your choice. It takes 1 hour to arrive at your destination, no matter the distance.</p>
			<p class="indent">During your travel other stops may occur and are determined by the GM. If you or any friendly creature chooses to take a short rest while traveling and regains hit points at the end of the short rest by spending one or more Hit Dice, you also regain an extra 1d10 hit points.</p>
			<p class="indent">There are countless train stops, each of which includes a unique train stop number. When you first gain the ability to cast this spell, you learn the code for two destinations, determined by the GM. You can learn additional codes during your adventures. You can commit a new code sequence to memory after studying it for 1 minute.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 minute</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a blank ticket and high quality ink worth at least 50 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Crustacean Form" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_CRUSTACEAN_FORM">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a large ethereal crustacean form around your body, which protects and aids you in combat. For the duration, your Armor Class becomes 20 (if it wasn't already higher), you gain a swimming speed of 40 feet, and you gain blindsight out to a range of 30 feet. In addition, you can use your bonus action to make a melee weapon attack using your claws. This attack uses your spell attack bonus and deals 1d10 bludgeoning damage on a hit.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, your ethereal shell has a damage threshold of 15 hit points. A damage threshold gives you immunity to all damage unless it is an amount of damage equal to or greater than the threshold value, in which case you take damage as normal. Any damage that fails to meet or exceed the shell's damage threshold is considered superficial and doesn't reduce any hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
			<set name="level">6</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a rust crab shell</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Dara Blocks" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_DARA_BLOCKS">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create five 1-foot cubes of magical force known as dara blocks. Each dara block appears in a different unoccupied space of your choice within range and becomes magically fixed in place. The blocks are invisible to all creatures except you and any creature you designate when you cast the spell. A creature that can see the dara blocks (including one benefiting from see invisibility or truesight) sees a luminous cube made of a transparent, dark green light.</p>
			<p class="indent">A block fixed in the air can hold up to 5,000 pounds of weight. More weight causes the block to fall. A creature can use an action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC, moving the fixed block up to 10 feet on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, you can create two additional dara blocks for each slot level above 3rd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pinch of sand and a piece of pottery</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Divine Arrow" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_DIVINE_ARROW">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Warlock, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You fire an angelic arrow from a bow made of light that materializes in your hands. Make a ranged spell attack against a creature within range. On a hit, the target takes 4d10 force damage, and until the spell ends, it becomes vulnerable to one of the following damage types of your choice: acid, cold, fire, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder. If a creature has immunity to the selected damage type, it instead has resistance to that type for the duration; if a creature has resistance to the selected damage type, it loses that resistance for the duration.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">force</set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a pearl worth 100 gp</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Duplicate" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_DUPLICATE">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create an exact replica of an object you can see within range that weighs no more than 25 pounds. At first glance, the two objects are indistinguishable from each other and the duplicate functions as if it were the original, except for any magical properties the original object may have. The duplicate disappears when the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">If a creature uses its action to examine the duplicate, the creature can determine that it is a replica with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd or 3rd level, the duration of the spell increases to 8 hours. When you use a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the duration of the spell increases to 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">5 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">copper powder and wax</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ember Belly" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_EMBER_BELLY">
		<supports>Bard, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You swallow the oil consumed in the casting of the spell. Once before the spell ends, you can exhale the oil as a bonus action, igniting it as you expel it from your body. Each creature in a 5-foot-wide, 30-foot-long line must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 2d10 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you exhale the oil, the spell ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">fire</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">copper powder and wax</set>
			<set name="duration">8 hours</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Festival King" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_FESTIVAL_KING">
		<supports>Bard, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose a creature within range. A gaudy crown and cape appear on the target, accompanied by a disembodied arrangement of brass instruments. For the duration, the target becomes the Festival King and has an aura of importance that emanates from them. Any creature that moves to a space within 20 feet of the Festival King for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, must make a Charisma saving throw. A creature that can't be charmed succeeds on this saving throw automatically. On a failed save, the creature becomes enamored with the Festival King, chanting, and dancing around them. While under the effects of the spell, creatures spend their action and bonus action at the start of their turn giving all of their attention and admiration to the Festival King.</p>
			<p class="indent">If a creature starts its turn outside of the Festival King's aura, it is no longer under the effects of the spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">force</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small ribbon</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Forest Guard" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_FOREST_GUARD">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a Small animated shrub, which grows from the ground in an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within range. The shrub has a number of human-like characteristics, such as a wooden body and face, but it lacks hands and arms and can't move.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature hostile to you that moves to a space within 10 feet of the shrub for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, is targeted by the shrub's leaf attack. The shrub makes a ranged weapon attack, using your spell attack modifier. On a hit, a creature takes 1d4 slashing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">On your turn, you can use a bonus action to make a shrub use its leaf attack against one creature within 10 feet of it. If multiple shrubs created by you are within 10 feet of the target, this attack deals 1d4 slashing damage per shrub on a hit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can create one additional shrub for every two slot levels above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">slashing</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Gift" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_GIFT">
		<supports>Bard, Paladin, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose a creature you can see within range. You take 1d20 necrotic damage, and the target regains hit points equal to the amount of damage you took.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Jolt" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_JOLT">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A jolt of electricity springs from your hand towards a creature you can see within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d8 lightning damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Alternatively, you can target a machine within range and temporarily turn it on, allowing it to function as if it were whelmed by a spirit or permanently enchanted. Machines targeted by this spell stay powered for 18 seconds before turning back off. For a machine to function using this spell, it must still be in working condition.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">lightning</set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Light Snare" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_LIGHT_SNARE">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A shimmering band of light streaks toward a target within range and envelops it in a spectacular burst of light. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target is restrained, and it is magically fixed in place until the end of its next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Bonus Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mass Levitate" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_MASS_LEVITATE">
		<supports>Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Six creatures or loose objects of your choice that you can see within range rise vertically, up to 20 feet, and remain suspended there for the duration. The spell can levitate a target that weighs up to 500 pounds. An unwilling creature that succeeds on a Constitution saving throw is unaffected.</p>
			<p class="indent">A target can move only by pushing or pulling against a fixed object or surface within reach (such as a wall or a ceiling), which allows it to move as if it were climbing. You can change the altitude of any number of targets by up to 20 feet in either direction on your turn. If you are one of the targets, you can move up or down as part of your move. Otherwise, you can use your action to move the targets, which must remain within the spell's range.</p>
			<p class="indent">When the spell ends, the targets float gently to the ground if it is still aloft.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small leather loop</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Monkey's Grasp" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_MONKEYS_GRASP">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a large, ethereal monkey paw that rises up and grasps at a Huge or smaller creature on the ground you can see within range. The paw attempts to grapple the target, using your spellcasting ability modifier to resolve the grapple. If you lose the contest, the paw disappears, and the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">While grappled by the paw, a target takes 1d8 necrotic damage at the start of each of its turns. The target can use its action to attempt to escape the grapple as normal. When the grapple is broken, the paw disappears, and the spell ends.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd, summoning a separate monkey paw for each target. When you do so, the spell doesn't end until the last paw disappears. The creatures must be within 60 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">necrotic</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">120 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Mushroom Ballista" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_MUSHROOM_BALLISTA">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You touch one to three pieces of ammunition and imbue them with a unique toadstool magic, causing them to grow plump green mushrooms around or at the tip of the ammunition.</p>
			<p class="indent">When a creature is hit with a ranged weapon attack using the ammunition, it takes an extra 1d6 poison damage and must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is pushed back a number of feet equal to the damage taken (rounded up to the nearest 5 feet) to a maximum of 15 feet. Whether the attack hits or misses, the spell then ends on that piece of ammunition.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you cast this spell again, the spell ends on any ammunition still affected by your previous casting.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">poison</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Bonus Action</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Obscure Object" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_OBSCURE_OBJECT">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>An object you can see within range becomes invisible until the spell ends. The object can be no larger than a 5-foot cube, and it can't be worn by a creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 hour</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Origami Bird Swarm" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_ORIGAMI_BIRD_SWARM">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A swarm of eight origami birds erupts from the stack of papers consumed in the casting of the spell and flies toward a creature you can see within range. If the target is within 30 feet of you when you cast the spell, the swarm collides with the target, dealing 8d6 slashing damage to it, and the birds disappear.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the target is farther than 30 feet away from you when you cast the spell, the swarm travels at a rate of 30 feet per round in the direction of the target, ignoring difficult terrain and moving around creatures and other obstructions as needed. While the swarm is traveling, it obstructs a 5-foot-cube area as if it were a Medium creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">While the swarm is traveling, it can be attacked. It has an AC equal to your spell save DC. For every attack that hits the swarm, the number of birds in the swarm is reduced by one.</p>
			<p class="indent">At the start of your turn on the round that the swarm reaches its target, the target takes 1d6 slashing damage for each bird remaining in the swarm. The birds then disappear.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th level or higher, the number of birds in the swarm increases by two for each slot level above 5th; if the target is within 30 feet of you when you cast the spell, it takes an extra 2d6 slashing damage for each slot level above 5th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">slashing</set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">300 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">fine papers worth 10 gp, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Pacify Monster" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_PACIFY_MONSTER">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You attempt to pacify a creature you can see within range. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails the save, it is pacified by you until the spell ends. A pacified creature can't attack, cast a spell that affects an enemy, or deal damage to another creature. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 4th. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gull's feather</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Pacify Person" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_PACIFY_PERSON">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You attempt to pacify a humanoid you can see within range. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. If it fails the save, it is pacified by you until the spell ends. A pacified creature can't attack, cast a spell that affects an enemy, or deal damage to another creature. The target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional humanoid for each slot level above 1st. The humanoids must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a gull's feather</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Pillar of Force" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_PILLAR_OF_FORCE">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You swiftly stomp your foot, conjuring a pillar of wood or stone that thrusts out from underneath your feet and towards a creature you can see within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 2d12 bludgeoning damage, and if the target is Huge or smaller, it is pushed 10 feet away from you. The ground in a straight line between you and your target becomes difficult terrain, with each 5-foot-square portion requiring at least 1 minute to clear by hand.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d12 for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Plummet" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_PLUMMET">
		<supports>Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You conjure an enormous glowing force, which wraps around a flying creature within range, and attempt to pull it out of the air. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it is pulled to the ground and takes falling damage as normal (1d6 bludgeoning damage for every 10 feet it falls, to a maximum of 20d6). On a successful save, the creature drops halfway to the ground and takes no damage.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">300 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Pogmo's Pot" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_POGMOS_POT">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a cast iron pot in an unoccupied space on the ground within range. All objects within 20 feet of the pot that are neither worn nor carried and that weigh no more than 10 pounds are instantly sucked inside Pogmo's strange container, whether they look like they should fit or not. All objects are stored in an extradimensional space inside the pot until the spell ends, at which point the pot vanishes and the objects it contained appear on the ground in its space.</p>
			<p class="indent">For the duration, the pot remains sealed shut and the objects inside can't be accessed until the spell ends. The pot is 1 foot wide and 1 foot tall. It can easily be moved or carried and always weighs 15 pounds, regardless of how much the objects it contains weigh. The pot is immune to all damage, but it can be dispelled.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Rageful Nimbus" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_RAGEFUL_NIMBUS">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose a creature within range, which can be yourself. A pristine, fluffy white cloud appears above the target and follows them for the duration. If the target takes damage from a hostile creature you can see, you can use your reaction to make a ranged spell attack from the cloud, provided that creature is within 60 feet of the target. On a hit, the creature takes 2d8 lightning damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for every two slot levels above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">lightning</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Bonus Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of water</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Resilient Friendship" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_RESILIENT_FRIENDSHIP">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You magically assist a creature within range, granting it the benefits of the Help action. If the target you helped successfully accomplishes the task by the start of your next turn, you gain 1d4 temporary hit points, which last for 1 hour.</p>
			<p class="indent">The number of temporary hit points you gain increases when you reach 5th level (1d6), 11th level (1d8), and 17th level (1d10).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Enchantment</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">5 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Retrieve" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_RETRIEVE">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause an object within range that isn't being worn or carried to fly to your open hand. The object must weigh no more than 10 pounds or the spell fails.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Bonus Action</set>
			<set name="range">15 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Root Grab" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_ROOT_GRAB">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You cause roots to reach out and grasp at the creature that provoked the opportunity attack, hindering its movement. The creature's speed is reduced by 10 feet until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a creature provokes an opportunity attack from you</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Sand Structure" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SAND_STRUCTURE">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A wall of sand that is 5 feet tall, 5 feet wide, and 1 foot thick materializes from the ground up in an unoccupied space that you can see within range. The sand functions as solid stone while in its wall form. The wall has AC 13 and 10 hit points. Reducing the wall to 0 hit points destroys it and might cause connected walls to collapse at the GM's discretion. You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it. When the spell ends, the wall crumbles back into sand.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you cast the spell as a ritual, the wall lasts until it is destroyed or dismissed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small piece of seaglass</set>
			<set name="duration">1 minute</set>
			<set name="isRitual">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Shared Vision" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SHARED_VISION">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You target a willing creature that is familiar to you and within range. For the duration or until the target dismisses the effect on itself as an action, the target can see through your eyes, gaining the benefits of any special senses that you have. During this time the target can swap between their own vision and your vision as a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional willing creature for each slot level above 2nd.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">1 mile</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a glass eye</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Spell Signature" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SPELL_SIGNATURE">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Paladin, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As you cast the spell you draw out the potent scents trapped within all magic. Choose a magical effect you are aware of that's within range. The effect releases a scent specific to the creature that created it. If you are familiar with the creature, you automatically know that the magical effect was created by them.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you are not familiar with the creature, you can make an ability check using your spellcasting ability modifier and add your proficiency bonus to it. Refer to the table below to determine what information you are able to glean from the scent. When succeeding on a DC check, you also learn previous information given from lower DCs.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>DC 5—You learn the type of creature that created the magical effect.</li>
				<li>DC 10—If the creature has a class, you learn what it is.</li>
				<li>DC 15—You learn if the creature is affiliated with an organization.</li>
				<li>DC 20—You learn the name of the creature.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Divination</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a rosewood match</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Sprout Foliage" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SPROUT_FOLIAGE">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You sprout and rapidly grow a lush leafy foliage that covers the entirety of your body. When casting this spell, you can choose if the foliage has other features, such as flowers or berries.</p>
			<p class="indent">While prone and motionless, you are indistinguishable from a normal bush. If a creature hasn't observed you move or act, it must succeed on an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC to discern that you aren't a bush. To become disguised again from a creature that has discerned you for what you are, you must take the Hide action while you're unseen by the creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">For the duration, you can use your action to create and hurl a pinecone, berry, or flower bud. When you do so, make a ranged spell attack against a creature within 30 feet of you. On a hit, the target takes bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your spellcasting ability modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">flower seeds</set>
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Storm Stallion" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_STORM_STALLION">
		<supports>Druid, Paladin, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Choose a 5-foot-cube space that you can see within range. A Medium elemental stallion appears in that space out of a twisting gust of wind and charges in a direction you choose in a straight line up to 60 feet long. If the stallion appears in a space occupied by a creature that is Medium or smaller, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be carried along with the stallion as it moves. A creature can choose to fail this saving throw.</p>
			<p class="indent">Each creature in the stallion's path (excluding the creature it's carrying, if any) must make a Dexterity saving throw, taking 6d8 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The stallion then vanishes.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 5th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 4th.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
			<set name="level">4</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">the stem of a windbloom</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Submerge" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SUBMERGE">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell creates a magical link between a body of water within range and another body of water, at any location within 500 miles, on the same plane of existence. You must have seen or touched the destination body of water at least once before. For the duration, any creature can step into the target body of water and exit from the destination body of water by using 5 feet of movement.</p>
			<p class="indent">Both bodies of water must be large enough for the creature attempting to pass through to become fully submerged. If either body of water isn't large enough for the creature to become fully submerged, there's a 25 percent chance that the creature exits from a random body of water on the same plane of existence.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">10 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Summon Jack-o'-lantern" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SUMMON_JACK_O_LANTERN">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard, Spell Saving Throw</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A giant jack-o'-lantern rapidly grows around up to four Medium or smaller creatures or one Large creature within a 5-foot radius centered on a point you can see within range. An unwilling creature in the area can make a Dexterity saving throw, leaping 5 feet outside the jack-o'-lantern on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">While inside the jack-o'-lantern, creatures can only see through its eyes and mouth, which are on one side of the jack-o'-lantern, selected by you when you cast this spell. The creatures can make attacks with ranged or reach weapons only from this side. Creatures outside the jack-o'-lantern only see a warm, glowing light when looking into its mouth or eyes. While the jack-o'-lantern remains, no creature in, or outside of it can pass or reach through it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The jack-o'-lantern weighs 5,000 pounds, has an AC of 15, and has 100 hit points. The lantern naturally loses 20 hit points every year. When the lantern is reduced to 0 hit points, it is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">bits of jack-o'-lantern</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Summon Vehicle" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SUMMON_VEHICLE">
		<supports>Bard, Ranger, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You summon a bicycle or moving machine in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. The vehicle can be no larger than a 5-foot cube, and it can only carry one creature that is Medium or smaller. The vehicle has a walking speed of 60 feet, which you can use while riding it, provided you have at least one free hand to operate the vehicle.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can end the spell early by using an action to dismiss it. When the spell ends, the vehicle vanishes.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">5 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a small piece of rubber</set>
			<set name="duration">10 minutes</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Swallow Magic" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SWALLOW_MAGIC">
		<supports>Bard, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You chomp down on the threads of magic left in the air after the triggering spell fails to affect you, swallowing the now latent magic and gaining one of the following effects of your choice:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You regain hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier.</li>
				<li>Your speed increases by 15 feet until the end of your next turn.</li>
				<li>Once before the end of your next turn, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to one ability check of your choice.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when a spell cast by another creature fails to affect you</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Switched Form" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_SWITCHED_FORM">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>This spell allows you to change the appearance of two humanoids that you can see within range. Each target takes on an illusory disguise, making it look like the other target—including its armor, clothing, weapons, and other belongings on its person. Each creature can seem 1 foot shorter or taller; the disguise otherwise replicates the other target's physical features as accurately as possible. The spell lasts for the duration, unless you use your action to dismiss it sooner.</p>
			<p class="indent">The changes wrought by this spell fail to hold up to physical inspection. For example, if this spell causes a creature to gain a cape from its disguise, objects pass through the cape, and anyone who touches it would feel nothing or would feel the creature's back or shoulders. If this spell causes a creature to appear thinner than it is, the hand of someone who reaches out to touch the creature would bump into it while it was seemingly still in midair.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature can use its action to inspect a target and make an Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If it succeeds, it becomes aware that the target is disguised.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Tamh Gon's Fiery Festival Feast" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_TAMH_GONS_FIERY_FESTIVAL_FEAST">
		<supports>Bard, Cleric, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You sanctify a meal in an extravagant show of thrown spices and twirling dance. Those who partake in the meal are granted the curry blessings of the great festival spirit Tamh Gon. The feast takes 1 hour to consume and the beneficial effects don't set in until this hour is over. Up to twelve creatures can participate in this feast.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature that partakes of the feast gains several benefits. The creature reduces its exhaustion level by one, its speed increases by 10 feet, and it gains a +2 bonus to Dexterity saving throws. It can also activate the effects of the <i>Ember Belly</i> spell one time while the benefits of the feast last. The feast's benefits last for 24 hours.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">5</set>
			<set name="school">Abjuration</set>
			<set name="time">10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">an uncommon ingredient, which the spell consumes</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Task" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_TASK">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>With a flick of your wrist, you magically complete a small and simple task, such as flipping a book page, buttering bread, or heating a cup of tea, without any physical interaction. The task can't include anything that is intended to inflict a harmful effect on a creature and must be something you'd normally be able to accomplish without the use of magic. The spell fails if the target of the task has total cover from you.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three tasks active at a time, and you can dismiss one of them as a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">0</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">15 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Up to 1 hour</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Transparency" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_TRANSPARENCY">
		<supports>Bard, Sorcerer, Warlock, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You temporarily become invisible to stop yourself from being discovered by the triggering creature. Until the end of your next turn, you remain invisible and your steps make no sound, regardless of the surface you are moving across. Anything you are wearing or carrying is invisible as long as it is on your person. The spell ends early if you attack or cast a spell.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Illusion</set>
			<set name="time">1 reaction, which you take when your location would be revealed to a creature while you are hidden or unseen</set>
			<set name="range">Self</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">1 round</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Vegetable Blade" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_VEGETABLE_BLADE">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Paladin, Ranger, Sorcerer</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A lush bunch of vegetable fronds suddenly springs from the ground in an unoccupied space you can see within range. As a bonus action, a creature can pull the fronds from the ground, revealing a root vegetable of your choice that has been grown in the shape of a blade. For the duration, a creature can use the vegetable blade as a melee weapon with which it is proficient. The blade deals 1d12 slashing damage on a hit (adding your ability modifier to the damage roll as normal), and it has finesse. Additionally, on subsequent turns, the wielder or one of its allies can use a bonus action to take a bite out of the blade. Doing so heals the creature for a number of hit points equal to the blade's damage die + your spellcasting ability modifier. Once a creature has taken a bite out of the blade, its damage die is reduced by one size—from a d12 to a d10, for example. If the blade is reduced beyond a d4, it is destroyed and the spell ends early.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">slashing</set>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">30 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a strip of grass</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Water Bullet" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_WATER_BULLET">
		<supports>Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard, Spell Attack</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a sphere of swirling water that spins rapidly in your hand or mouth before you hurl it at a creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes bludgeoning damage based on how far it is away from you.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>1-10 feet: 5d6</li>
				<li>11-60 feet: 4d6</li>
				<li>61-90 feet: 3d6</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">bludgeoning</set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">90 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Whelm Weapon" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_WHELM_WEAPON">
		<supports>Bard, Druid, Ranger, Sorcerer, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Up to three weapons of your choice that you can see within range become enveloped by water. Roll a d4; for the duration, any damage dealt by the targeted weapons is reduced by the number you rolled (to a minimum of 1).</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>At Higher Levels.</i></b> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target two additional weapons for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of seawater</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Wind Spirit" type="Spell" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_SPELL_WIND_SPIRIT">
		<supports>Paladin, Ranger, Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A turning tempest wind lifts you up and carries you to a creature you can see within range. The next time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack before the end of the turn, the attack deals an extra 2d6 slashing damage as the winds buffet the target.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">slashing</set>
			<set name="level">2</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">Bonus Action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">false</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent" />
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

</elements>
