<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Sheep Dragon Shepherd</name>
		<description>Sheep Dragon Shepherd from Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="monk-sheep-dragon-shepherd.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/obojima-tales-from-the-tall-grass/archetypes/monk-sheep-dragon-shepherd.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Sheep Dragon Shepherd" type="Archetype" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_MONK_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD">
		<supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The sheep dragon is often regarded as the epitome of goodness and authenticity on the island. These creatures are dedicated to freedom and unwavering kinship. Those shepherds living and training among the wandering sheep dragons learn to care deeply for those around them and understand how a flock works together to overcome obstacles. They must be ready to flee to safety yet know when to defend their herd. The role of a sheep dragon shepherd requires resilience, compassion, and a kind heart. Because of this, shepherds across the island are regarded by the people of Obojima as heroic and sometimes even mythic figures.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Historic Pasts</h5>
			<p>As the tale goes, the first shepherd was a wind spirit who went by the name Ventu. The spirit lived among the grass and called all that grazed the central fields of Obojima their friend, but of those creatures, none pleased Ventu more than the playful sheep dragon. In time Ventu and the sheep dragon became inseparable. The seasons would speed away, and still, the pair would frolic and parade the Gale Fields with careless glee. It's during this time that people say Ventu gifted the sheep dragon the ability to fly and control the winds.</p>
			<p class="indent">One day, as Ventu explored the fields, they noticed something unsettling in the distance. A great pillar of black smoke split the horizon in two. Ventu rushed across the rolling hills, only to be met by terrible disaster. A raging fire had scorched the southern fields and slowly crawled northward. Ventu, heartbroken at the thought of what might become of the sheep dragon just beyond the hillside, made the heroic choice to stand against the inferno by themself.</p>
			<p class="indent">To this day, it's unknown what became of Ventu, but the majestic sheep dragon stands as a testament to their kindness and bravery.</p>
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_HERDING_SHEEP" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_WIND_SHOT" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_INTERCEPTING_MANEUVER" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_TAKE_TO_THE_SKIES" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_GUIDE_TO_THE_HERD" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_HERDING_SHEEP" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_WIND_SHOT" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_INTERCEPTING_MANEUVER" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_TAKE_TO_THE_SKIES" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_GUIDE_TO_THE_HERD" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Herding Sheep" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_HERDING_SHEEP">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to herd your allies, calling them closer or moving them out of danger. As a bonus action, you can spend 1 or more ki points to cause a willing creature that you can see within 60 feet of you to move toward you or in any other direction. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks. If the creature moves toward you, it can move up to 15 feet per ki point spent; if it moves in any other direction, it can move up to 10 feet per ki point spent. A creature can't move in this way more than its speed would allow.</p>
			<p class="indent">At higher levels, when you use this feature you can target additional creatures. At 5th level you can target 2 creatures, 3 creatures at 10th, and 4 creatures at 15th.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can spend 1 or more ki points to cause {{ottg:sheep dragon shepherd:herding sheep:number}} willing creature(s) that you can see within 60 ft of you to move toward you or in any other direction. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks. If the creature moves toward you, it can move up to 15 ft per ki point spent; if it moves in any other direction, it can move up to 10 ft per ki point spent. A creature can't move in this way more than its speed would allow.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ottg:sheep dragon shepherd:herding sheep:number" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="ottg:sheep dragon shepherd:herding sheep:number" value="2" bonus="base" level="5" />
			<stat name="ottg:sheep dragon shepherd:herding sheep:number" value="3" bonus="base" level="10" />
			<stat name="ottg:sheep dragon shepherd:herding sheep:number" value="4" bonus="base" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Wind Shot" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_WIND_SHOT">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 6th level, you gain the ability to mimic the sheep dragon's wind pistol, blasting enemies with powerful gale forces at a distance. When you make an unarmed strike, you can instead choose to make a special attack, firing a compressed blast of air from your mouth. This ranged weapon attack has a range of 60 feet, and it uses the same attack bonus and damage die as your unarmed strike.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you hit a target with this special attack, you can choose to spend 1 ki point to force the target to make a Strength saving throw against your ki save DC. On a failed save, the target is knocked prone or pushed 10 feet away from you (your choice).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make an unarmed strike, you can instead choose to make a special attack, firing a compressed blast of air from your mouth. This ranged weapon attack has a range of 60 ft, and it uses the same attack bonus and damage die as your unarmed strike.
			Additionally, when you hit a target with this special attack, you can choose to spend 1 ki point to force the target to make a Strength saving throw (DC {{ki:dc}}). On a failed save, the target is knocked prone or pushed 10 ft away from you (your choice).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Intercepting Maneuver" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_INTERCEPTING_MANEUVER">
		<description>
			<p>Also at 6th level, your protective nature comes out in heightened moments of skillful deflection for a nearby ally. As a reaction, when a friendly creature within 10 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can spend 1 ki point to reduce the damage it takes by an amount equal to one roll of your Martial Arts die + your Dexterity modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When a friendly creature within 10 ft of you is hit by an attack, you can spend 1 ki point to reduce the damage it takes by an amount equal to 1d{{martial arts:dice}} + {{dexterity:modifier}}.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Take to the Skies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_TAKE_TO_THE_SKIES">
		<description>
			<p>By the time you reach 11th level, you've mastered a unique technique that lets you glide on the wind, just like a majestic sheep dragon. When you use your Step of the Wind, you also gain a flying speed equal to your walking speed. This flying speed lasts until the end of your turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you use your Step of the Wind, you simultaneously take both the Disengage and Dash action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use your Step of the Wind, you also gain a flying speed equal to {{speed}} ft. This flying speed lasts until the end of your turn.
			Additionally, when you use your Step of the Wind, you simultaneously take both the Disengage and Dash action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Guide to the Herd" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SHEEP_DRAGON_SHEPHERD_GUIDE_TO_THE_HERD">
		<description>
			<p>At 17th level, your vigilant watch of your companions while in the midst of combat allows you to give them cues as to when they should raise their defenses. Whenever you use your Patient Defense to gain the benefits of the Dodge action, you can spend 1 additional ki point to share that benefit with your allies. Each friendly creature that can see or hear you and is within 30 feet of you can immediately use its reaction to also gain the benefits of the Dodge action until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you use your Patient Defense to gain the benefits of the Dodge action, you can spend 1 additional ki point to share that benefit with your allies. Each friendly creature that can see or hear you and is within 30 ft of you can immediately use its reaction to also gain the benefits of the Dodge action until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
