<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Waxwork Rogue</name>
		<description>Waxwork Rogue from Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="rogue-waxwork.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/obojima-tales-from-the-tall-grass/archetypes/rogue-waxwork.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Waxwork Rogue" type="Archetype" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_ROGUE_WAXWORK">
		<supports>Roguish Archetype</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Waxwork rogues have a long history on the island of Obojima in dealing with the dangerous and the arcane. They're known for having an array of tools and tricks to delve into the most perilous of places and almost always coming back with treasures and tales. To a Waxwork rogue, any challenge or danger can be solved with a bit of wax, a pinch of smarts, and a whole lot of magic.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">In the Beginning</h5>
			<p>The Courier Brigade was created to carry packages between villages as well as guard merchant wagons through treacherous areas. But there are some areas on Obojima that are rife with the arcane, spirit dangers, and uncanny occurrences.</p>
			<p class="indent">Legend says that it was Lydia Starwright, Courier Brigade First Class, who, against all advice, sought out the aid of a powerful witch who was rumored to live within a hut of melted wax deep within the Land of Hot Water. It was there in that melted hut where the witch taught Lydia the arcane practices known only to certain spirits of the island, the ability to enchant wax and fire in wondrous ways. It was this knowledge that transformed Lydi into the first Waxwork Rogue.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lydia brought back this knowledge to the Courier Brigade, and formed the Waxworks Division, a dedicated group of arcane rogues who would volunteer for the most perilous assignments and deliveries of the Courier Brigade.</p>
			<p class="indent">In the present day, Waxwork rogues have transcended the ranks of the Courier Brigade, and their skill sets are practiced across the island.</p>
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_CONJURE_FLAME" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENTS" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_BURN_CYCLE" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_ADVANCED_ENCHANTMENTS" />
			<div element="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_SPIRIT_FLAME" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_CONJURE_FLAME" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENTS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_BURN_CYCLE" level="9" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_ADVANCED_ENCHANTMENTS" level="13" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_SPIRIT_FLAME" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Conjure Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_CONJURE_FLAME">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you learn the <i>Dancing Lights</i> cantrip (the lights appear as floating candles) and the <i>Produce Flame</i> cantrip.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You know the Dancing Lights cantrip (the lights appear as floating candles) and the Produce Flame cantrip.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DANCING_LIGHTS" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Wax Enchantments" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENTS">
		<description>
			<p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn wax enchantments, which are fueled by your ability to pull and manipulate magic from the Spirit Realm. These are represented by a number of wick points.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Maneuvers.</em></strong> You learn three enchantments of your choice, which are detailed under "Enchantments" below.</p>
			<p class="indent">You learn two additional enchantments of your choice at 5th, 10th, and 15th level. Each time you learn new enchantments, you can also replace one enchantment you know with a different one.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Saving Throws.</em></strong> Some of your enchantments require creatures to make a saving throw to resist the enchantment's effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Enchantment save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence or Charisma modifier (your choice)</strong></p>
			</center>
			<p><strong><em>Wick Points.</em></strong> You have 3 wick points, which represent your current ability to harness the magic from the Spirit Realm. Manipulating the magic from another realm and pulling its energy into an object, even one as small and simple as a candle, can be both physically and mentally taxing. When you spend a wick point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which you regain all of your expended wick points.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whenever you gain a level in this class, you gain 1 additional wick point.</p>
			<h4>Enchantments</h4>
			<p>The enchantments are presented in alphabetical order.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Blooming Light.</em></strong> As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to ignite a dark green candle, which burns in a similar hue, shedding dim light in a 10-foot radius centered on itself. Creatures in the candle's light are hidden from divination magic, and they can't be targeted by such magic or perceived through magical scrying sensors. This effect lasts for 1 hour.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Bocha Glue Wax.</em></strong> Bocha glue is a delicate mixture of the finest waxes available and a collection of ingredients known only to the Waxwork Rogues. When enchanted properly, it can temporarily hold any two objects together. As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to create an adhesive bond between two objects using just a small amount of bocha glue. The two objects remain bound together for 24 hours, at which point the enchantment fades and the two objects are separated. A creature within reach of the objects can use an action to make a Strength (Athletics) check against your Enchantment save DC, breaking the bond early on a success.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Burning Delay (5th Level Required).</em></strong> You can spend 3 additional wick points to simultaneously activate Burning Delay when you use one of the following candle enchantments: candle pop, fish fat candle, or detonate. When you do so, you delay that enchantment's activation by 1 round, 1 minute, or 10 minutes (your choice).</p>

			<p><strong><em>Candle Pop.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can spend 2 wick points to ignite and hurl a misshapen yellow candle at a creature you can see within 60 feet of you. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw to avoid being partially encased in wax as the candle explodes on impact. On a failed save, the target is restrained by the wax. At the end of each of its turns, a restrained target can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Consuming Flame (10th Level Required).</em></strong> When you see a hostile creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell, you can use your reaction and spend 3 wick points to quickly ignite the flame of a thin white candle and cast <i>Counterspell</i>. If the spell was successfully countered and was 3rd level or lower, you can spend an additional 2 wick points to reactivate this ability and store the spell inside your candle.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding the candle, you can cast any spell stored in it. The spell uses the slot level, spell save DC, spell attack modifier, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell. Once the spell has been cast, the candle is sundered and becomes unusable. A spell can be stored inside a candle for 24 hours, after which the spell fades and is no longer able to be used.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Delicacy.</em></strong> As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to imbue the tart flavor of a <strong>Pyramid Melon</strong> and the healing properties of a river spirit into your candle. As a bonus action, a creature can consume the candle, causing it to regain 1d6 hit points and providing enough nourishment to sustain it for one day. A candle holds this enchantment for 24 hours, after which the properties of delicacy fade. You can have no more than 2 candles with this enchantment at a time.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Detonate (5th Level Required).</em></strong> As an action, you can spend 3 wick points to ignite and throw a dark black candle at a point you can see within 60 feet of you. A brilliant eruption of flame sweeps out from the candle, causing each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point to make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 2d6 fire damage and 2d8 thunder damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. When you use this enchantment, you can spend additional wick points to increase the fire damage dealt by 1d6 for each additional wick point spent.</p>
			<p class="indent">The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Fish Fat Candle.</em></strong> As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to ignite and throw an oily brick of blubber candle wax that lands in an unoccupied space you can see on the ground within 60 feet of you. One round after the candle lands, it emits a cloud of colorful smoke that creates a heavily obscured area in a 20-foot radius centered on it. The candle continues to spew smoke for 1 minute and creates a visible trail in the sky that can be seen from 10 miles away.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Flooding Abundance.</em></strong> As an action, you can spend 2 wick points to ignite and throw a tea light candle into an unoccupied space you can see on the ground within 60 feet of you. After landing, the candle melts rapidly, bubbling and boiling with an overwhelming amount of wax, which flows over and fills a 15-foot-square centered on the candle. The wax remains for 1 minute. It is flammable, and a 5-foot square of wax exposed to fire burns away in 3 rounds, dealing 2d6 fire damage to any creature that starts its turn in the fire. All spaces covered in the wax are difficult terrain for the duration.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Iron Seal.</em></strong> As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to melt and press the wax seal of iron onto any door or object with a lid. Once imbued with your seal, the object becomes magically shut and can't be opened unless a creature makes a successful Strength (Athletics) check against your Enchantment save DC, at which point the seal breaks. The iron seal lasts until it is broken or dispelled (as if it were a 1st-level spell). You can use an action to touch one of your iron seals and end its effects early.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Lost Wax Carving.</em></strong> Using the lost form of wax carving you craft a detailed replica of an object. When using the wax carving technique, you can spend 2 wick points over the course of 10 minutes to produce the effects of the <i>Duplicate</i> spell. The object you duplicate can be no larger than a 1-foot cube.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Maker's Mark.</em></strong> When you make an attack with a one-handed weapon as part of the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 wick point to make an unarmed strike as part of the same action using a signet ring. This attack deals bludgeoning damage equal to 1d4 + your Dexterity modifier, plus an extra 1d6 fire damage. This attack can benefit from your Sneak Attack, provided you haven't already dealt your Sneak Attack damage this turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this enchantment once per turn.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Shielding Seal.</em></strong> As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to melt and press the wax seal of shielding onto a willing creature or object, protecting it from incoming damage. The target of the seal gains 5 temporary hit points, which last for 24 hours. You can grant an additional 5 temporary hit points for each additional wick point spent, to a maximum of 15 temporary hit points. You can only have one shielding seal active at a time. Creating a shielding seal while another seal of the same type is already active ends the effects of the initial seal early.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Spark Shower.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can spend 2 wick points to bring your free hand to your mouth, igniting your next breath. Exhaling creates a dazzling shower of sparks aimed toward a creature within 5 feet of you. You have advantage on the next weapon attack roll you make against the target this turn, and the target can't make opportunity attacks until the end of your turn.</p>

			<p><strong><em>Waxlings.</em></strong> By reaching through the veil and into the Spirit Realm, you can temporarily pull and trap a minor spirit within a candle, granting the candle sentience. As an action, you can spend 2 wick points to summon a waxling, casting the <i>Find Familiar</i> spell with the following changes:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>In place of an animal familiar, you instead imbue life into a candle, which causes it to grow appendages and eyes.</li>
				<li>Your waxling familiar uses the statistics of a rat.</li>
				<li>You can command the familiar to use its action to touch a flammable object that isn't being worn or carried and ignite it.</li>
				<li>The familiar sheds bright light in a 5-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.</li>
				<li>You can't temporarily dismiss the familiar.</li>
				<li>The familiar is dismissed permanently after 1 hour or when it is reduced to 0 hit points.</li>
				<li>You can have more than one of these familiars at a time.</li>
			</ul>

			<p><strong><em>Wick Whip.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can spend 3 wick points to ignite a 10-foot length of candlewick that has been soaking in the stomach acid of a dragon frog. The flames burn at an intense heat that warps the air around them, shedding bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. The wick burns for 1 minute, during which you can use it as a melee weapon that you're considered proficient with. It deals 3d4 fire damage on a hit (adding your ability modifier to the damage roll as normal), and it has the finesse, light, and reach properties.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You learn wax enchantments, which are fueled by your ability to pull and manipulate magic from the Spirit Realm. These are represented by {{level:rogue}} wick points. You regain all wick points when you finish a short rest. Your enchantment save DC is {{ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc:ability" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc:ability" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc" value="ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc:ability" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Wax Enchantment (Level 3)" supports="OTTG Wax Enchantments" number="3" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Wax Enchantment (Level 5)" supports="OTTG Wax Enchantments" number="2" level="5" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Wax Enchantment (Level 10)" supports="OTTG Wax Enchantments" number="2" level="10" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Wax Enchantment (Level 15)" supports="OTTG Wax Enchantments" number="2" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Burn Cycle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_BURN_CYCLE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 9th level, you can ignite your weapons in a flash of hot white flames when you successfully catch an enemy off guard. When you deal Sneak Attack damage on your turn, you can spend wick points to deal extra fire damage to the target, in addition to the weapon's damage. The extra damage is 1d6 for each wick point spent, to a maximum of 4d6.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you deal Sneak Attack damage on your turn, you can spend wick points to deal extra fire damage to the target, in addition to the weapon's damage. The extra damage is 1d6 for each wick point spent, to a maximum of 4d6.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Advanced Enchantments" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_ADVANCED_ENCHANTMENTS">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 13th level, some of your enchantments become more potent. You now use the alternate enchantments features found below. If you have yet to learn any of the following enchantments, you may learn one as part of this feature.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Blooming Light.</em></strong> Starting at 13th level, the effects of blooming light lasts for 8 hours.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Burning Delay.</em></strong> Starting at 13th level, you can delay the effects of your candle enchantments by 1 round, 3 rounds, 1 minute, 10 minutes, or 1 hour.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Candle Pop.</em></strong> Starting at 13th level, candle pop affects the target and each creature within 5 feet of it.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Delicacy.</em></strong> Starting at 13th level, the creature regains 1d12 hit points, instead of 1d6, and you can have up to 4 candles with this enchantment at a time.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Maker's Mark.</em></strong> Starting at 13th level, maker's mark has no limit to the number of times you can use it per turn.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Shielding Seal.</em></strong> Starting at 13th level, you can have up to three shielding seals active at a time, instead of one.</p>
			<p><strong><em>Waxlings.</em></strong> Starting at 13th level, you can spend 3 wicks points as an action, instead of 2, to summon two waxlings simultaneously.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:blooming light:duration" value="8" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:delicacy:die" value="12" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:delicacy:amount" value="4" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Spirit Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_SPIRIT_FLAME">
		<description>
			<p>At 17th level, you learn to craft a specialty candle made of pink wax. As a bonus action, you can ignite this candle, which burns for 1 minute. As long as the burning candle is on your person, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The wick point cost of your enchantments is reduced by 1.</li>
				<li>You have immunity to fire damage.</li>
				<li>Spirits have disadvantage on attack rolls against you.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">If you fall prone while the burning candle is on your person, you must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or the candle is extinguished early.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can ignite this candle, which burns for 1 minute. As long as the burning candle is on your person, you gain the following benefits: &#13;
			• The wick point cost of your enchantments is reduced by 1. &#13;
			• You have immunity to fire damage. &#13;
			• Spirits have disadvantage on attack rolls against you. &#13;
			If you fall prone while the burning candle is on your person, you must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or the candle is extinguished early.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!--Wax Enchantments-->
	<element name="Blooming Light" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_BLOOMING_LIGHT">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to ignite a dark green candle, which burns in a similar hue, shedding dim light in a 10-foot radius centered on itself. Creatures in the candle's light are hidden from divination magic, and they can't be targeted by such magic or perceived through magical scrying sensors. This effect lasts for 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 1 wick point to ignite a dark green candle, which burns in a similar hue, shedding dim light in a 10-ft radius centered on itself. Creatures in the candle's light are hidden from divination magic, and they can't be targeted by such magic or perceived through magical scrying sensors. This effect lasts for {{ottg:waxwork rogue:blooming light:duration}} hour(s).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:blooming light:duration" value="1" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Bocha Glue Wax" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_BOCHA_GLUE_WAX">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Bocha glue is a delicate mixture of the finest waxes available and a collection of ingredients known only to the Waxwork Rogues. When enchanted properly, it can temporarily hold any two objects together. As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to create an adhesive bond between two objects using just a small amount of bocha glue. The two objects remain bound together for 24 hours, at which point the enchantment fades and the two objects are separated. A creature within reach of the objects can use an action to make a Strength (Athletics) check against your Enchantment save DC, breaking the bond early on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>Bocha glue is a delicate mixture of the finest waxes available and a collection of ingredients known only to the Waxwork Rogues. When enchanted properly, it can temporarily hold any two objects together. You can spend 1 wick point to create an adhesive bond between two objects using just a small amount of bocha glue. The two objects remain bound together for 24 hours, at which point the enchantment fades and the two objects are separated. A creature within reach of the objects can use an action to make a Strength (Athletics) check (DC {{ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc}}), breaking the bond early on a success.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Burning Delay" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_BURNING_DELAY">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<prerequisite>5th Level Required</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:5]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can spend 3 additional wick points to simultaneously activate Burning Delay when you use one of the following candle enchantments: candle pop, fish fat candle, or detonate. When you do so, you delay that enchantment's activation by 1 round, 1 minute, or 10 minutes (your choice).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 3 additional wick points to simultaneously activate Burning Delay when you use one of the following candle enchantments: candle pop, fish fat candle, or detonate. When you do so, you delay that enchantment's activation by 1 round, 1 minute, or 10 minutes (your choice).</description>
			<description level="13">You can spend 3 additional wick points to simultaneously activate Burning Delay when you use one of the following candle enchantments: candle pop, fish fat candle, or detonate. When you do so, you delay that enchantment's activation by 1 round, 3 rounds, 1 minute, 10 minutes, or 1 hour (your choice).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Candle Pop" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_CANDLE_POP">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, you can spend 2 wick points to ignite and hurl a misshapen yellow candle at a creature you can see within 60 feet of you. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw to avoid being partially encased in wax as the candle explodes on impact. On a failed save, the target is restrained by the wax. At the end of each of its turns, a restrained target can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 2 wick points to ignite and hurl a misshapen yellow candle at a creature you can see within 60 ft of you. The target must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc}}) to avoid being partially encased in wax as the candle explodes on impact. On a failed save, the target is restrained by the wax. At the end of each of its turns, a restrained target can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</description>
			<description level="13">You can spend 2 wick points to ignite and hurl a misshapen yellow candle at a creature you can see within 60 ft of you. Each creature with 5 ft of the target must make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc}}) to avoid being partially encased in wax as the candle explodes on impact. On a failed save, the target is restrained by the wax. At the end of each of its turns, a restrained target can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Consuming Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_CONSUMING_FLAME">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<prerequisite>10th Level Required</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:10]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you see a hostile creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell, you can use your reaction and spend 3 wick points to quickly ignite the flame of a thin white candle and cast <i>Counterspell</i>. If the spell was successfully countered and was 3rd level or lower, you can spend an additional 2 wick points to reactivate this ability and store the spell inside your candle.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding the candle, you can cast any spell stored in it. The spell uses the slot level, spell save DC, spell attack modifier, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell. Once the spell has been cast, the candle is sundered and becomes unusable. A spell can be stored inside a candle for 24 hours, after which the spell fades and is no longer able to be used.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>When you see a hostile creature within 60 feet of you casting a spell, you can use your reaction and spend 3 wick points to quickly cast Counterspell. If the spell was successfully countered and was 3rd level or lower, you can spend an additional 2 wick points to reactivate this ability and store the spell inside your candle. &#13;
			While holding the candle, you can cast any spell stored in it. The spell uses the slot level, spell save DC, spell attack modifier, and spellcasting ability of the original caster, but is otherwise treated as if you cast the spell. Once the spell has been cast, the candle is sundered and becomes unusable. A spell can be stored inside a candle for 24 hours, after which the spell fades and is no longer able to be used.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Delicacy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_DELICACY">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to imbue the tart flavor of a <strong>Pyramid Melon</strong> and the healing properties of a river spirit into your candle. As a bonus action, a creature can consume the candle, causing it to regain 1d6 hit points and providing enough nourishment to sustain it for one day. A candle holds this enchantment for 24 hours, after which the properties of delicacy fade. You can have no more than 2 candles with this enchantment at a time.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>A creature can consume the candle, causing it to regain 1d{{ottg:waxwork rogue:delicacy:die}} hp and providing enough nourishment to sustain it for one day. A candle holds this enchantment for 24 hours, after which the properties of delicacy fade. You can have no more than {{ottg:waxwork rogue:delicacy:amount}} candles with this enchantment at a time.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:delicacy:die" value="6" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="ottg:waxwork rogue:delicacy:amount" value="2" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Detonate" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_DETONATE">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<prerequisite>5th Level Required</prerequisite>
		<requirements>[level:5]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can spend 3 wick points to ignite and throw a dark black candle at a point you can see within 60 feet of you. A brilliant eruption of flame sweeps out from the candle, causing each creature in a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on that point to make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 2d6 fire damage and 2d8 thunder damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. When you use this enchantment, you can spend additional wick points to increase the fire damage dealt by 1d6 for each additional wick point spent.</p>
			<p class="indent">The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 3 wick points to ignite and throw a dark black candle at a point you can see within 60 ft of you. A brilliant eruption of flame sweeps out from the candle, causing each creature in a 20-ft-radius sphere centered on that point to make a Dexterity saving throw (DC {{ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc}}). A target takes 2d6 fire damage and 2d8 thunder damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. When you use this enchantment, you can spend additional wick points to increase the fire damage dealt by 1d6 for each additional wick point spent. &#13;
			The fire spreads around corners. It ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Fish Fat Candle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_FISH_FAT_CANDLE">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to ignite and throw an oily brick of blubber candle wax that lands in an unoccupied space you can see on the ground within 60 feet of you. One round after the candle lands, it emits a cloud of colorful smoke that creates a heavily obscured area in a 20-foot radius centered on it. The candle continues to spew smoke for 1 minute and creates a visible trail in the sky that can be seen from 10 miles away.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 1 wick point to ignite and throw an oily brick of blubber candle wax that lands in an unoccupied space you can see on the ground within 60 ft of you. One round after the candle lands, it emits a cloud of colorful smoke that creates a heavily obscured area in a 20-ft radius centered on it. The candle continues to spew smoke for 1 minute and creates a visible trail in the sky that can be seen from 10 miles away.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Flooding Abundance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_FLOODING_ABUNDANCE">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can spend 2 wick points to ignite and throw a tea light candle into an unoccupied space you can see on the ground within 60 feet of you. After landing, the candle melts rapidly, bubbling and boiling with an overwhelming amount of wax, which flows over and fills a 15-foot-square centered on the candle. The wax remains for 1 minute. It is flammable, and a 5-foot square of wax exposed to fire burns away in 3 rounds, dealing 2d6 fire damage to any creature that starts its turn in the fire. All spaces covered in the wax are difficult terrain for the duration.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 2 wick points to ignite and throw a tea light candle into an unoccupied space you can see on the ground within 60 ft of you. After landing, the candle melts rapidly, bubbling and boiling with an overwhelming amount of wax, which flows over and fills a 15-ft-square centered on the candle. The wax remains for 1 minute. It is flammable, and a 5-ft square of wax exposed to fire burns away in 3 rounds, dealing 2d6 fire damage to any creature that starts its turn in the fire. All spaces covered in the wax are difficult terrain for the duration.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Iron Seal" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_IRON_SEAL">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to melt and press the wax seal of iron onto any door or object with a lid. Once imbued with your seal, the object becomes magically shut and can't be opened unless a creature makes a successful Strength (Athletics) check against your Enchantment save DC, at which point the seal breaks. The iron seal lasts until it is broken or dispelled (as if it were a 1st-level spell). You can use an action to touch one of your iron seals and end its effects early.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 1 wick point to melt and press the wax seal of iron onto any door or object with a lid. Once imbued with your seal, the object becomes magically shut and can't be opened unless a creature makes a successful Strength (Athletics) check (DC {{ottg:waxwork rogue:wax enchantment:dc}}), at which point the seal breaks. The iron seal lasts until it is broken or dispelled (as if it were a 1st-level spell). You can use an action to touch one of your iron seals and end its effects early.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Lost Wax Carving" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_LOST_WAX_CARVING">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Using the lost form of wax carving you craft a detailed replica of an object. When using the wax carving technique, you can spend 2 wick points over the course of 10 minutes to produce the effects of the <i>Duplicate</i> spell. The object you duplicate can be no larger than a 1-foot cube.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>Using the lost form of wax carving you craft a detailed replica of an object. When using the wax carving technique, you can spend 2 wick points over the course of 10 minutes to produce the effects of the Duplicate spell. The object you duplicate can be no larger than a 1-ft cube.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Maker's Mark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_MAKERS_MARK">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you make an attack with a one-handed weapon as part of the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 wick point to make an unarmed strike as part of the same action using a signet ring. This attack deals bludgeoning damage equal to 1d4 + your Dexterity modifier, plus an extra 1d6 fire damage. This attack can benefit from your Sneak Attack, provided you haven't already dealt your Sneak Attack damage this turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this enchantment once per turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>When you make an attack with a one-handed weapon as part of the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 wick point to make an unarmed strike as part of the same action using a signet ring. This attack deals bludgeoning damage equal to 1d4 + {{dexterity:modifier}}, plus an extra 1d6 fire damage. This attack can benefit from your Sneak Attack, provided you haven't already dealt your Sneak Attack damage this turn. You can use this enchantment once per turn.</description>
			<description level="13">When you make an attack with a one-handed weapon as part of the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 wick point to make an unarmed strike as part of the same action using a signet ring. This attack deals bludgeoning damage equal to 1d4 + {{dexterity:modifier}}, plus an extra 1d6 fire damage. This attack can benefit from your Sneak Attack, provided you haven't already dealt your Sneak Attack damage this turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Shielding Seal" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_SHIELDING_SEAL">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can spend 1 wick point to melt and press the wax seal of shielding onto a willing creature or object, protecting it from incoming damage. The target of the seal gains 5 temporary hit points, which last for 24 hours. You can grant an additional 5 temporary hit points for each additional wick point spent, to a maximum of 15 temporary hit points. You can only have one shielding seal active at a time. Creating a shielding seal while another seal of the same type is already active ends the effects of the initial seal early.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 1 wick point to melt and press the wax seal of shielding onto a willing creature or object, protecting it from incoming damage. The target of the seal gains 5 temporary hp, which last for 24 hours. You can grant an additional 5 temporary hp for each additional wick point spent, to a maximum of 15 temporary hp. You can only have one shielding seal active at a time. Creating a shielding seal while another seal of the same type is already active ends the effects of the initial seal early.</description>
			<description level="13">You can spend 1 wick point to melt and press the wax seal of shielding onto a willing creature or object, protecting it from incoming damage. The target of the seal gains 5 temporary hp, which last for 24 hours. You can grant an additional 5 temporary hp for each additional wick point spent, to a maximum of 15 temporary hp. You can have up to 3 shielding seals active at a time. Creating a shielding seal while another seal of the same type is already active ends the effects of the initial seal early.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Spark Shower" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_SPARK_SHOWER">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, you can spend 2 wick points to bring your free hand to your mouth, igniting your next breath. Exhaling creates a dazzling shower of sparks aimed toward a creature within 5 feet of you. You have advantage on the next weapon attack roll you make against the target this turn, and the target can't make opportunity attacks until the end of your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 2 wick points to bring your free hand to your mouth, igniting your next breath. Exhaling creates a dazzling shower of sparks aimed toward a creature within 5 ft of you. You have advantage on the next weapon attack roll you make against the target this turn, and the target can't make opportunity attacks until the end of your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Waxlings" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_WAXLINGS">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>By reaching through the veil and into the Spirit Realm, you can temporarily pull and trap a minor spirit within a candle, granting the candle sentience. As an action, you can spend 2 wick points to summon a waxling, casting the <i>Find Familiar</i> spell with the following changes:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>In place of an animal familiar, you instead imbue life into a candle, which causes it to grow appendages and eyes.</li>
				<li>Your waxling familiar uses the statistics of a rat.</li>
				<li>You can command the familiar to use its action to touch a flammable object that isn't being worn or carried and ignite it.</li>
				<li>The familiar sheds bright light in a 5-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.</li>
				<li>You can't temporarily dismiss the familiar.</li>
				<li>The familiar is dismissed permanently after 1 hour or when it is reduced to 0 hit points.</li>
				<li>You can have more than one of these familiars at a time.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 2 wick points to summon a waxling, casting the Find Familiar spell with the following changes. You can spend 3 wicks points as an action, instead of 2, to summon two waxlings simultaneously. &#13;
			• In place of an animal familiar, you instead imbue life into a candle, which causes it to grow appendages and eyes. &#13;
			• Your waxling familiar uses the statistics of a rat. &#13;
			• You can command the familiar to use its action to touch a flammable object that isn't being worn or carried and ignite it. &#13;
			• The familiar sheds bright light in a 5-ft radius and dim light for an additional 10 ft. &#13;
			• You can't temporarily dismiss the familiar. &#13;
			• The familiar is dismissed permanently after 1 hour or when it is reduced to 0 hp. &#13;
			• You can have more than one of these familiars at a time.</description>
			<description level="13">You can spend 2 wick points to summon a waxling, casting the Find Familiar spell with the following changes: &#13;
			• In place of an animal familiar, you instead imbue life into a candle, which causes it to grow appendages and eyes. &#13;
			• Your waxling familiar uses the statistics of a rat. &#13;
			• You can command the familiar to use its action to touch a flammable object that isn't being worn or carried and ignite it. &#13;
			• The familiar sheds bright light in a 5-ft radius and dim light for an additional 10 ft. &#13;
			• You can't temporarily dismiss the familiar. &#13;
			• The familiar is dismissed permanently after 1 hour or when it is reduced to 0 hp. &#13;
			• You can have more than one of these familiars at a time.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Wick Whip" type="Archetype Feature" source="Obojima: Tales from the Tall Grass" id="ID_1985_OTTG_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WAXWORK_ROGUE_WAX_ENCHANTMENT_WICK_WHIP">
		<supports>OTTG Wax Enchantments</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, you can spend 3 wick points to ignite a 10-foot length of candlewick that has been soaking in the stomach acid of a dragon frog. The flames burn at an intense heat that warps the air around them, shedding bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. The wick burns for 1 minute, during which you can use it as a melee weapon that you're considered proficient with. It deals 3d4 fire damage on a hit (adding your ability modifier to the damage roll as normal), and it has the finesse, light, and reach properties.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="Wax Enchantment">
			<description>You can spend 3 wick points to ignite a 10-ft length of candlewick that has been soaking in the stomach acid of a dragon frog. The flames burn at an intense heat that warps the air around them, shedding bright light in a 15-ft radius and dim light for an additional 15 ft. The wick burns for 1 minute, during which you can use it as a melee weapon that you're considered proficient with. It deals 3d4 fire damage on a hit (adding your ability modifier to the damage roll as normal), and it has the finesse, light, and reach properties.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
