<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Magic Items</name>
		<description>Magic Items from Where Evil Lives</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="magic-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/where-evil-lives/magic-items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Aastrika's Crown" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_AASTRIKAS_CROWN">
		<description>
			<p><i>Aastrika's crown</i> is a relic Aastrika took from her previous commander after killing him. It has been infused with a shred of her power, and it magically resizes to fit its attuned wearer.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Blend with the Blaze.</em></strong> As an action, you can touch a Small or larger mundane flame. When you do, you take no damage from the fire, and you know the location of every Small or larger flame within 10 miles of you. As part of the action, you can teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of another flame you detect. This property can be used twice, and the crown regains all expended uses daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Fire Resistance.</em></strong> You have resistance to fire damage while wearing this crown.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Magma Transport.</em></strong> You know the location of all lava pools in the Molten Enclave. While you are within 10 feet of one of these lava pools, you can use an action to teleport yourself and up to one willing creature within 10 feet of you to an unoccupied space within 10 feet of any other lava pool in the lair.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, teleport, fire, resistance</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Bag of Eyes" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_BAG_OF_HOLDING">
		<description>
			<p>This lumpy green leather sack contains five eyeballs of varying colors. You can use your action to place an eyeball on a surface and utter the command word, causing the eyeball to meld into the surface and become invisible for the next 24 hours. The eyeball has normal vision and darkvision out to 60 feet and can look in every direction. You can have up to five eyeballs active at once.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can see through an active eyeball that is on the same plane of existence as you. During this time, you see as if you were in its space, gaining the benefits of the eyeball's darkvision, but you are blind with regard to your own senses. Switching your vision between eyeballs requires an action. Returning to your own senses doesn't require an action.</p>
			<p class="indent">After an eyeball has been active for 24 hours, it vanishes from the surface where it was placed. If the eyeball and the <i>bag of eyes</i> are on the same plane of existence, the eyeball returns to the bag. Otherwise, the eyeball is lost.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Blade of Forlorn Hope" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_BLADE_OF_FORLORN_HOPE">
		<description>
			<p>Gifted to vanguard Kitseth by the elder primordial of fire, this wide-bladed scimitar helps its wielder protect others, but with a disregard for self-preservation.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you hit a creature with the sword, it flares with a burning corona. You can either deal an extra 2d6 radiant damage to the target, or you can choose one ally you can see within 30 feet of the target to gain 2d6 temporary hit points.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Immolating Surge.</em></strong> Immediately after attacking a creature on your turn with the sword, you can take one additional action. At the end of this turn, you take 6d8 radiant damage. If this damage reduces you to 0 hit points, you die and your remains burn to nothing. Once this property is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">scimitar, action, radiant, damage, temporary hit points</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="scimitar">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Scimitar</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Draconic Visage" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE">		
		<description>
			<p>This mask bears the visage of a fearsome white-scaled dragon. When you finish a long rest, you can change the color of the mask's scales to another color on the <i>Draconic Visage</i> Color table.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you wear the mask, your body becomes covered in dragon scales, granting you a +1 bonus to AC and resistance to the damage type associated with the mask's color. You can speak and understand Draconic, and you have advantage on Charisma checks made to influence dragons.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you wear the mask and deal damage to a creature, you can deal an extra 3d10 damage of the type associated with the mask's color. The mask can deal extra damage in this way three times and regains all expended uses daily at dawn.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr> <td class="col-20">Color</td> <td>Damage Type</td> </tr>
				</thead>
				<tbody>
					<tr> <td>Black</td> <td>Acid</td> </tr>
					<tr> <td>Blue</td> <td>Lightning</td> </tr>
					<tr> <td>Green</td> <td>Poison</td> </tr>
					<tr> <td>Red</td> <td>Fire</td> </tr>
					<tr> <td>White</td> <td>Cold</td> </tr>
				</tbody>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">mask, acid, lightning, poison, fire, cold, resistance, damage, ac, advantage, charisma</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" alt="Draconic Visage" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Draconic Visage Color" supports="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_BLACK|ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_BLUE|ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_GREEN|ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_RED|ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_WHITE" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Black" type="Class Feature" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_BLACK">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Blue" type="Class Feature" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_BLUE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Green" type="Class Feature" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_GREEN">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Red" type="Class Feature" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_RED">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="White" type="Class Feature" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE_WHITE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_DRACONIC_VISAGE" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Essence of Shadowkeep" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_ESSENCE_OF_SHADOWKEEP">
		<description>
			<p>The <i>Essence of Shadowkeep</i> is a sentient fragment of the hellish influence permeating Shadowkeep, which takes the form of black mist. As an action, you can inhale the essence and attune to it instantly. You can exhale the essence as an action, ending your attunement to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">While attuned to the essence, your eyes turn red and you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You are resistant to necrotic damage.</li>
				<li>Your weapon attacks deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage.</li>
				<li>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can regain hit points equal to the damage dealt. Once you regain hit points in this way, you can't do so again until the next dusk.</li>
				<li>You know about effects created by the Devil's Influence in Shadowkeep.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> The <i>Essence of Shadowkeep</i> is a sentient, lawful evil item with an Intelligence of 14, a Wisdom of 15, and a Charisma of 18. When a creature isn't attuned to it, the essence has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet and can speak and understand Common. When a creature is attuned to it, the essence can sense everything its wielder senses and can only communicate telepathically with its wielder.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> Egotistical and domineering, the <i>Essence of Shadowkeep</i> is an ambitious force that craves action. The essence encourages its wielder to be decisive, choose action over words, and awe enemies with displays of might. If the wielder ignores the essence's advice three times in a row, a conflict between it and the wielder arises at the next sunset.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, necrotic, damage, resistance, evil, illrigger, paladin, warlock, hit points, sentience</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by an illrigger, paladin, or warlock of evil alignment">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" requirements="ID_ALIGNMENT_LAWFUL_EVIL|ID_ALIGNMENT_NEUTRAL_EVIL|ID_ALIGNMENT_CHAOTIC_EVIL" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Foresight Weapon" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_FORESIGHT_WEAPON">
		<description>
			<p>This weapon's haft is engraved with sigils of divination. You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. In combat, the weapon imparts subtle hints of the future to you, letting you predict a foe's defensive movements when you initially engage them. The first time you attack each creature during an encounter with this weapon, you have advantage on the attack roll. If that attack hits, maximize your weapon damage dice against the target.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you miss with an attack using this weapon, you can use your reaction to shift the flow of causality and turn the miss into a hit. Once you use this reaction, you can't do so again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">advantage, reaction</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_RANGED||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Foresight {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Kinesthetic Projection" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_KINESTHETIC_PROJECTION">
		<description>
			<p>Many warriors claim the sword they wield is an extension of themself—an allegory at best. But this shortsword, forged from viscera, bone, and shattered psyches, makes the statement literal. The sword's bony blade narrows into a handle, wrapped in fleshy tendrils.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Curse.</em></strong> When you attune to this shortsword, it fuses to your hand, stitching your bones to the handle and binding your flesh to the sinewy wraps. You can't let go of the sword or use your fused hand to hold another object. This effect ends and the sword detaches if you are targeted by a <i>cure ailment</i> power or <i>remove curse</i> spell.</p>
			<p class="indent">While attached to your hand, whether you remain attuned to the sword or not, you have violent nightmares whenever you close your eyes, and you take 1d6 psychic damage whenever you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Kinesthetic Projection.</em></strong> You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this shortsword, and it deals an extra 1d6 psychic damage on a hit.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Visceral Reach.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can spend 2 Hit Dice to extend this weapon's reach by 10 feet for 1 minute. Additionally, for the duration, you can use an action to make a melee weapon attack against a creature within 30 feet of you. On a hit, the target must succeed on a DC 17 Strength saving throw or be pulled up to 25 feet directly toward you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shortsword, psychic, damage, curse, bonus action, saving throw, reach</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shortsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shortsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Lava Crucible" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_LAVA_CRUCIBLE">
		<description>
			<p>This 1-foot-diameter bowl is made of scorched and polished red dragon scales and engraved with fiery red runes on its exterior. While you carry the crucible, you are immune to fire damage and can speak and understand Draconic and Ignan.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, while you hold this crucible, you can use a bonus action to speak a command word and cause it to fill with lava. The lava is harmless to you, but other creatures who touch it take 33 (6d10) fire damage. While the crucible is filled with lava, you can use it in the following ways:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>As an action, you make a melee attack with the lava against a creature or mundane object within 5 feet of you. Make an attack with a +11 bonus to the attack roll.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>The attack empties the lava from the bowl and deals 33 (6d10) fire damage on a hit.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You cast <i>scrying</i> (spell save DC 20). Your target's image appears in the lava.</li>
				<li>You cast <i>conjure elemental</i>, but only to call forth fire elementals.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>You can use another bonus action to speak the command word again and harmlessly empty the lava from the crucible.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, action, attack, spells, scrying, conjure elementals, bonus action, fire, damage, immunity, draconic, ignan, language</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_FIRE" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_MM_LANGUAGE_IGNAN" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Millstone of Grinding" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_MILLSTONE_OF_GRINDING">
		<description>
			<p>This 5-ton, 10-foot-diameter flat stone bears the inscription "All is Grist."</p>
			<p class="indent">While the mill is operational, the millstone can pulverize any Small or Tiny mundane object placed in the hole at its center. The object becomes a pinch of magic flour. As an action, a creature can add this flour to water, causing the object to return to its original form.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Monocle of Secrets" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_MONOCLE_OF_SECRETS">
		<description>
			<p>While you wear this gold-rimmed monocle, you have advantage on ability checks made to find secret doors and traps.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you can use an action while holding a mundane object to learn that object's exact value, the materials used to create it, and whether it is genuine or counterfeit.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, advantage</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Nine Lives" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_NINE_LIVES">
		<description>
			<p>The black pommel of Baron Uthrak's longsword is set with nine bloodstone gems: three gray and six red.</p>
			<p class="indent">You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you hit with an attack roll using it, the target takes an extra 1d6 necrotic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bloodstones.</em></strong> The sword has 3 charges left, one for each gray bloodstone.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you fail a saving throw while holding this sword, you can expend 1 charge to succeed instead (no action required). When you do so, you take 2d6 necrotic damage, which can't be reduced in any way, and the sword drains some of your blood into one of the remaining gray bloodstones, turning the stone red.</p>
			<p class="indent">The sword loses this property while it has no charges remaining.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you deal damage to a Dragon with <i>Nine Lives</i> while the sword has fewer than 9 charges, the sword regains 1 charge and one of the sword's red bloodstones turns gray. Once the sword has regained a charge in this way, it can't do so again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">longsword, necrotic, damage</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="longsword">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="weapon">Longsword</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Overmatter Totem" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_OVERMATTER_TOTEM">
		<description>
			<p>This totem is made out of a petrified overmind tongue encased in hard, translucent resin. While holding it, you can use an action to detach one ear, eye, or hand from your body. The body part has AC 10, hit points equal to half your hit point maximum, a flying speed equal to half your greatest movement speed, and it can hover.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your detached body part acts on your turn and follows your telepathic commands. Each body part can only take the following actions:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ear.</em></strong> Your ear can hear. Anything your detached ear hears, you hear. On your turn, your ear can use an action to make a Wisdom (Perception) check to hear.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Eye.</em></strong> Your eye can see and has any special senses you have, except for tremorsense. Anything your detached eye sees, you see. On your turn, your eye can use an action to make a Wisdom (Perception) check to see.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Hand.</em></strong> Your hand can carry and manipulate Tiny objects.</p>
			<p class="indent">On your turn, your hand can use an action to interact with an object you can see or to make one attack using a light weapon against a target you can see. This attack uses your attack bonus and ability score modifier.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your detached body part is within 5 feet of you, it can use an action to reattach to you. If your body part is reduced to 0 hit points or is ever more than 60 feet away from you, it falls to the ground, lifeless, and must be reattached manually. Reattaching a body part manually takes 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, perception, attack</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Psi Lenses" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_PSI_LENSES">
		<description>
			<p><i>Psi lenses</i> come in pairs, with each shard of iridescent glass made to fit flush with the other's irregularly chiseled edge. When you touch one lens while the other is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use an action to teleport to the space containing the other lens, or the closest unoccupied space if the lens's space is occupied.</p>
			<p class="indent">After a lens is used to teleport, the pair can't be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, teleport</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Rod of the Sovereign's Servant" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_ROD_OF_THE_SOVEREIGNS_SERVANT">
		<description>
			<p>While holding this rod of blackened bone, you can cast the <i>speak with dead</i> spell without expending a spell slot.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, while you hold the rod, you can cast the following spells using your spell save DC: <i>animate dead</i> as a 5th-level spell, <i>bestow curse</i>, <i>geas</i>, and <i>raise dead</i>. Once the rod has been used to cast one of these four spells, it can't be used to cast that spell again until the next dusk.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spellcaster, spells, speak with dead, animate dead, bestow curse, geas, raise dead</set>
			<set name="category">Rods</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Rod</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Sands of War" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_SANDS_OF_WAR">
		<description>
			<p>This sand table is filled with black volcanic sand. It is 15 feet long, 5 feet wide, and 3 feet tall. While you touch the table, you have advantage on Intelligence (History) checks to recall military lore and on Charisma (Intimidation) checks.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you use an action to speak the table's command phrase—"Prepare for war" in Infernal—the table turns into a 10-inch-tall, 3-inch-wide hourglass that weighs half a pound and is filled with black volcanic sand. You can speak the phrase again as an action to turn the hourglass back into a table, provided the hourglass has enough space to expand.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you carry the hourglass, you are resistant to fire damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, while you hold the hourglass, you can use a bonus action to flip it and give yourself supernatural tactical insight. For 10 minutes, when you make an attack roll or saving throw, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw. Once this bonus action is used, it can't be used again until the following dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature in possession of the hourglass can use an action to smash it on a solid surface. The hourglass is destroyed, and it explodes in a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on it. Each creature in that area must make a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw, taking 44 (8d10) fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">advantage, history, intimidation, fire, resistance, damage, saving throw, action, bonus action</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_FIRE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shield of Shadow Form" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIELD_OF_SHADOW_FORM">
		<description>
			<p>While holding this shield, you have a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you can use an action to transform yourself and everything you wear and carry into a shadowy cloud for 10 minutes. The effect ends if you drop to 0 hit points or use an action to end it.</p>
			<p class="indent">While in this form, your only method of movement is a flying speed of 10 feet. You can enter and occupy the space of another creature. When you end your turn in another creature's space, that creature takes 6d8 necrotic damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">You have resistance to mundane damage, and you have advantage on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws. You can pass through small holes, narrow openings, and even mere cracks, though you treat liquids as if they were solid surfaces. You can't fall and remain hovering in the air even when stunned or otherwise incapacitated.</p>
			<p class="indent">While in the form of a shadowy cloud, you can't talk or manipulate objects, and any objects you were carrying or holding can't be dropped, used, or otherwise interacted with. You can't attack, cast spells, or manifest powers.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use the shield to transform into a shadowy cloud, that property can't be used again until the following dusk.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shield, action, transformation</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shield">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Shadow Form</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shtriga Nonna's Pot of Plenty" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_SHTRIGA_NONNAS_POT_OF_PLENTY">
		<description>
			<p>This black iron pot weighs only 2 pounds. As an action, you can speak one of the following command phrases to activate its effect:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Boil, Boil, Until You Spoil.</em></strong> The cauldron fills with a hearty stew. It creates enough stew to feed fifteen Humanoids. The food is tasty and seasoned well, and spoils if uneaten after 24 hours.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Bubble, Bubble, Toil and Trouble.</em></strong> The cauldron fills with stew, as if you said "Boil, boil, until you spoil,"but the stew is poisoned. A creature who consumes the stew must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or be poisoned for 24 hours.</p>
			<p>Once the pot has been used in either of these ways, the pot can't be used again until the next dusk.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, food, saving throw, poisoned</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Soul Lamp" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_SOUL_LAMP">
		<description>
			<p>Swirling soul energy fills the glass globe of this lantern.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lantern has 6 charges. As an action, you can speak the lantern's command word and expend 1 charge to summon a <strong>specter</strong> residing within the lantern. The specter appears in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you. They know and can speak any language you know, obey your verbal commands, and act immediately after you in the initiative order. The specter is destroyed after 1 hour or when it drops to 0 hit points. The lamp can only have one specter summoned at a time.</p>
			<p class="indent">The lantern regains 1 charge when a creature who isn't a Construct or Undead dies within 20 feet of the lantern, allowing the lamp to draw their soul into it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, summon, spector</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Spear of Gael Wode" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_SPEAR_OF_GAEL_WODE">
		<description>
			<p>This spear was awarded to Vairae in recognition of their accomplishments on the battlefield, but it now lies discarded in the High Mage's vaults.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. While holding it, you ignore difficult terrain and you are resistant to piercing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spear also has 5 charges. You can expend 1 charge to cast the <i>tree stride</i> spell from it. In addition, when you make a weapon attack with the spear, you can expend 1 charge to cause grasping vines to erupt from the spear's tip.</p>
			<p class="indent">The attack's target and each enemy within 5 feet of them must succeed on a DC 20 Strength saving throw or be restrained by the entangling plants. A creature can use their action to make a DC 20 Strength check, freeing themself or a restrained creature within their reach on a success.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spear regains 1d4 + 1 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spear, piercing, resistance, spell, tree stride, saving throw</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="spear">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
			<set name="weapon">Spear</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PIERCING" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Spell Form of Erasure" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_SPELL_FORM_OF_ERASURE">
		<description>
			<p>This fractal sphere is an informationally hyperdense arcane formula from the void. You can decipher it with 1 hour of study.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once deciphered, the sphere can be used to perform a 1-hour ritual, which up to three other spellcasters within 10 feet of the sphere can participate in. At the ritual's culmination, the sphere is destroyed, and each participant can expend one spell slot. You must make a DC 40 Intelligence (Arcana) check, with a bonus equal to the combined level of the expended spell slots.</p>
			<p class="indent">On a success, choose a specific entity. Every sentient being in the timescape who didn't participate in the ritual loses all memory of the chosen entity, and the entity's name is erased from all records. On a failure, the GM chooses an entity to be erased. If the check fails by 10 or more, you and all participants are also erased and die.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ritual</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Sun Eater Staff" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_SUN_EATER_STAFF">
		<description>
			<p>This lengthy staff of black wood has veins of black opal and obsidian running through it, and it feels cool to the touch.</p>
			<p class="indent">This staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff that grants a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The staff has 10 charges and regains 1d6 + 4 charges daily at midnight.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells.</em></strong> While holding the staff, you can use an action to expend 1 or more of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC: <i>acid arrow</i> (2 charges), <i>blight</i> (4 charges), <i>darkness</i> (1 charge), <i>fog cloud</i> (1 charge), or <i>wall of force</i> (5 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Consume Light.</em></strong> You can expend 1 charge as an action to extinguish any light sources of your choice that you can see within 120 feet of you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Fire Immunity.</em></strong> When you take fire damage while holding the staff, you can expend 1 charge as a reaction.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain immunity to fire damage until the start of your next turn, including against the triggering effect.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">action, spells, acid arrow, blight, darkness, fog cloud, wall of force, reaction, fire, immunity</set>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type">Staff</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="charges">10</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="The Closing Argument" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_THE_CLOSING_ARGUMENT">
		<description>
			<p>This golden archangel's feather exudes gravitas. The feather can be used as a quill that never runs out of bloodred ink.</p>
			<p class="indent">While you hold the quill, you have advantage on ability checks made to create and interpret contracts, deeds, and other official documentation, and you have advantage on ability checks made to conduct a legal dispute or negotiation.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when a creature (including you) uses <i>The Closing Argument</i> to sign a contract or other legal document, they can't willingly break the terms of the contract while the document exists. This effect can't control the actions of any creature who didn't sign the contract, nor can it empower a signatory to perform impossible actions. When this quill is used to sign a legal document, it supplies ink for 5 minutes (allowing more than one creature to sign), then the ink ceases to flow and no creature can use it to sign a document until a month has passed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">advantage</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Wand of Restoration" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_WAND_OF_RESTORATION">
		<description>
			<p>This wand has 6 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 2 of its charges to cast the <i>lesser restoration</i> spell from it, or 4 charges to cast the <i>greater restoration</i> spell from it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The wand regains 1d4 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll a d20. On a roll of 1, the wand crumbles into dust and is destroyed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spells, lesser restoration, greater restoration</set>
			<set name="category">Wands</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="type">Wand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="charges">6</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Watch of Prospecting" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_WATCH_OF_PROSPECTING">
		<description>
			<p>This silver pocket watch can detect the presence of items made of gold. Its second hand ticks loudly when you are within 30 feet of an item that is worth at least 100 gp, partially or entirely made of gold, and not worn or carried by another creature.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you have advantage on ability checks made to find hidden treasure.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">advantage, gold</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Xaantikorijek's Looking Glass" type="Magic Item" source="Where Evil Lives" id="ID_MCDM_WEL_MAGIC_ITEM_XAANTIKORIJEKS_LOOKING_GLASS">
		<description>
			<p>This handheld silver mirror is made from a portion of Xaantikorijek's Glass Cavern, and the back shows his thoughtful visage. While you carry the mirror, you are resistant to lightning and thunder damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, while you hold the mirror and can see a creature or object in its reflection, you can ask the mirror a question about the reflected creature or object's past. The mirror answers the question by magically changing the reflection, showing an event from the subject's past. The mirror can only show events that have occurred on the Mundane World. Once the mirror has shown an answer to a question, it can't be used in this way again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">lightning, thunder, resistance</set>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_LIGHTNING" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_THUNDER" />
		</rules>
	</element>

</elements>
