<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Barding</name>
		<description>Barding from The Lord of the Rings Roleplaying</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="race-barding.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/lord-of-the-rings-roleplaying/races/race-barding.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Barding" type="Race" source="The Lord of the Rings Roleplaying" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_RACE_BARDING">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">He was a descendant in long line of Girion, Lord of Dale, whose wife and child had escaped down the Running River from the ruin long ago.</p>
			<p>The Bardings are Northmen of noble origins hailing from Wilderland, far off to the east. They rebuilt their city of Dale from its ashes after the slaying of the Dragon Smaug and they earned a new prosperity trading with nearby kingdoms of Elves and Dwarves.</p>
			<p class="indent">Each year, Barding merchants reach new faraway lands, as they look outside their borders to expand their trade and influence. Sometimes, warriors follow in their wake, hoping to prove their mettle against worthy adversaries, inspired by their King's slaying of the Dragon.</p>
			<h4>Description</h4>
			<p>Strong in body and fearless in spirit, the Northmen are the denizens of Middle-earth that many consider to be nearest in kin to the Men of the West. They are strong-limbed, with fair hair, although dark or even black hair is not unknown. Barding men tend to keep beards, and often let their hair grow to reach their shoulders. Women adventurers braid their hair in long, tight tresses.</p>
			<p class="indent">When abroad they may be recognised by their gear, as they often carry equipment of superior make. Unlike most denizens of Wilderland, Bardings prefer to use swords over axes, and naturally favour the bow, after the example of their King.</p>
			<h4>Typical Names</h4>
			<p>Like most Northmen, Bardings often name their children after a renowned ancestor or relative, or choose a name beginning with the same sound or sharing one element with that of the father (whose name is often given with their first name when introduced formally—for example, Lifstan, son of Leiknir, or Ingrith, daughter of Ingolf).</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Sample Female Names:</strong> Aldrif, Asfrid, Asny, Astrith, Bera, Bergdis, Dagny, Dalla, Eilif, Erna, Eydis, Estrild, Frida, Geira, Gerda, Grimhild, Gundrid, Gunnhild, Halla, Halldis, Hild, Holma, Inga, Ingirun, Ingrith, Kelda, Lif, Linhild, Ragna, Runa, Saldis, Sigga, Signy, Solveig, Thora, Thorhild, Thorleif, Ulfhild, Ulfrun, Una, Vigdis, Walda.</li>
				<li><strong>Sample Male Names:</strong> Aegir, Arn, Brandulf, Domarr, Erland, Farald, Gautarr, Hafgrim, Hjalmar, Ingolf, Ketilmund, Kol, Kolbeinn, Leiknir, Lodin, Lomund, Magni, Mord, Munan, Nari, Nefstan, Nerulf, Oddmarr, Ornolf, Ottarr, Reinald, Runolf, Sandarr, Saxulf, Sigdan, Sigfast, Sigvald, Sigward, Sigmund, Skarf, Skefill, Smidur, Steinarr, Torwald, Ulfarr, Unnarr, Valbrand.</li>
			</ul>
			<h4>Cultural Traits</h4>
			<p>Your character gains the following benefits based on their cultural heritage.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength and Charisma scores each increase by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Adventuring Age.</em></strong> Between 18–40 years of age. Bardings rarely become adventurers before their 18th year, and retire in their forties, when they return home to serve their family and folk.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Bardings average between 5 and 6 feet tall, tending toward the higher end. Your size is Medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Archers of Dale.</em></strong> You have proficiency with the great bow.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Starting Virtue.</em></strong> You gain one cultural virtue of your choice.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Trading People.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Persuasion skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read and write Westron and Dalish, a language that can be described as a very old form of the Common Speech.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Standard of Living: Prosperous.</em></strong> The city of Dale and nearby Esgaroth are successful trading towns. Those among the Bardings who choose a life of adventure are usually members of less affluent families—yet, their wealth is still superior to that of most of the denizens of Eriador.</p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_FLP_LRRP_INFORMATION_STARTING_GEAR" />
			</div>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Aegir, Arn, Brandulf, Domarr, Erland, Farald, Gautarr, Hafgrim, Hjalmar, Ingolf, Ketilmund, Kol, Kolbeinn, Leiknir, Lodin, Lomund, Magni, Mord, Munan, Nari, Nefstan, Nerulf, Oddmarr, Ornolf, Ottarr, Reinald, Runolf, Sandarr, Saxulf, Sigdan, Sigfast, Sigvald, Sigward, Sigmund, Skarf, Skefill, Smidur, Steinarr, Torwald, Ulfarr, Unnarr, Valbrand</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Aldrif, Asfrid, Asny, Astrith, Bera, Bergdis, Dagny, Dalla, Eilif, Erna, Eydis, Estrild, Frida, Geira, Gerda, Grimhild, Gundrid, Gunnhild, Halla, Halldis, Hild, Holma, Inga, Ingirun, Ingrith, Kelda, Lif, Linhild, Ragna, Runa, Saldis, Sigga, Signy, Solveig, Thora, Thorhild, Thorleif, Ulfhild, Ulfrun, Una, Vigdis, Walda</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_RACE_HUMAN" />
			<stat name="strength" value="1" requirements="!(ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI||ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_BACKGROUND_ASI)" />
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" requirements="!(ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI||ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_BACKGROUND_ASI)" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Custom Ability Score Improvement +1 (Barding)" supports="Custom Ability Score Increase 1" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_ASI,!ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_BACKGROUND_ASI" number="2" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />

			<grant type="Language" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_LANGUAGE_WESTRON" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_LANGUAGE_DALISH" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language" supports="Custom Race Language||LRRP Westron||LRRP Barding Language" number="2" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_LANGUAGE" />

			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_RACIAL_TRAIT_BARDING_ARCHERS_OF_DALE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_RACIAL_TRAIT_BARDING_STARTING_VIRTUE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_RACIAL_TRAIT_BARDING_TRADING_PEOPLE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Archers of Dale" type="Racial Trait" source="The Lord of the Rings Roleplaying" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_RACIAL_TRAIT_BARDING_ARCHERS_OF_DALE">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency with the great bow.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGBOW" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Simple/Martial Weapon or Tool (Archers of Dale)" supports="Weapon||Tool" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Starting Virtue" type="Racial Trait" source="The Lord of the Rings Roleplaying" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_RACIAL_TRAIT_BARDING_STARTING_VIRTUE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain one cultural virtue of your choice. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Feat" name="Virtue (Starting Virtue)" supports="LRRP Cultural Virtue" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Trading People" type="Racial Trait" source="The Lord of the Rings Roleplaying" id="ID_FLP_LRRP_RACIAL_TRAIT_BARDING_TRADING_PEOPLE">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency in the Perception skill. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" requirements="!ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Customized Skill Proficiency (Trading People)" supports="Skill" requirements="ID_WOTC_TCOE_OPTION_CUSTOMIZED_PROFICIENCY" />
		</rules>
	</element>

</elements>
