<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Path of the Muscle Wizard</name>
		<description>Path of the Muscle Wizard from Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack</description>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="barbarian-muscle-wizard.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/FreshRoyal/elements-partnered/master/partnered/valdas-spire-of-secrets-player-pack/archetypes/barbarian-muscle-wizard.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Path of the Muscle Wizard" type="Archetype" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_BARBARIAN_PATH_OF_THE_MUSCLE_WIZARD">
		<supports>Barbarian Subclass</supports>
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Be a Buff, Angry "Wizard"</p>
			<p>You're a wizard! Perhaps you went to wizarding school on a football scholarship or just picked up a book at the gym and started reading. No matter how you got here, you're a wizard, one that just coincidentally has massive, rippling muscles. You have the big dumb hat and the book filled with gibberish and everything!</p>
			<p class="indent">You gently remind others, often by beating them to a pulp and cracking their bones, that your magical powers shouldn't be questioned. You're a good wizard—the best one, even! And only a fool would say otherwise.</p>
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_UNARGUABLE_WIZARDRY" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_CANTRIPS" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_MAGIC_RESISTANCE" />
			<div element="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_I_CAST_FIST" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_UNARGUABLE_WIZARDRY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_CANTRIPS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_MAGIC_RESISTANCE" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_I_CAST_FIST" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 3: Unarguable Wizardry" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_UNARGUABLE_WIZARDRY">
		<description>
			<p>Your unquestionable legitimacy (and immense pectoral muscles) give you Advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks made to convince others that you are, in fact, a wizard.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, if someone questions your legitimate magical prowess, you can take a Reaction to enter your Rage until the end of your next turn. This Rage can't be extended and doesn't expend a use of your Rage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Unarguable Wizardry">
			<description>You have Advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks made to convince others that you are, in fact, a wizard. &#13;
			Additionally, if someone questions your legitimate magical prowess, you can take a Reaction to enter your Rage until the end of your next turn. This Rage can't be extended and doesn't expend a use of your Rage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 3: 'Cantrips'" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_CANTRIPS">
		<description>
			<p>You can call upon your "magic" to cast "Cantrips" in combat. Once on each of your turns when you hit a target with a Strength-based attack, you can use one of the following "Cantrips" of your choice.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Mage Hand.</i></b> You can push the target up to 5 feet straight away from yourself if it is Large size or smaller. While your Rage is active, you can push the target up to 10 feet instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Shocking Grasp.</i></b> The force of your strike is quite shocking. The target can't make Opportunity Attacks until the end of the current turn. While your Rage is active, it can't make Opportunity Attacks until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>True Strike.</i></b> You really, truly strike, dealing an extra 1d6 damage to the target. The damage has the same type as the weapon or Unarmed Strike used for the attack. While your Rage is active, you add half your Barbarian level (round down) to the extra damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="'Cantrips'" usage="1/Turn">
			<description>Once when you hit a target with a Strength-based attack, you can use one of the following "Cantrips" of your choice: &#13;
			• Mage Hand. You can push the target up to 5 ft straight away from yourself if it is Large size or smaller. While your Rage is active, you can push the target up to 10 ft instead. &#13;
			• Shocking Grasp. The target can't make Opportunity Attacks until the end of the current turn. While your Rage is active, it can't make Opportunity Attacks until the start of your next turn. &#13;
			• True Strike. You deal an extra 1d6 damage to the target. The damage has the same type as the weapon or Unarmed Strike used for the attack. While your Rage is active, you add {{level:barbarian:half}} to the extra damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 6: 'Spells'" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>Your "magic" is powerful enough to cast every "spell" that exists (and no one can prove otherwise without broken ribs). However, you only prepared the following "spells" today. While your Rage is active, you can use each of the following "Spells" once. When you do so, you can't use that "Spell" again until you finish a Long Rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Burning Hands.</i></b> You can push the target up to 5 feet straight away from yourself if it is Large size or smaller. While your Rage is active, you can push the target up to 10 feet instead.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Magic Missile.</i></b> The force of your strike is quite shocking. The target can't make Opportunity Attacks until the end of the current turn. While your Rage is active, it can't make Opportunity Attacks until the start of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Shield.</i></b> You really, truly strike, dealing an extra 1d6 damage to the target. The damage has the same type as the weapon or Unarmed Strike used for the attack. While your Rage is active, you add half your Barbarian level (round down) to the extra damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS_BURNING_HANDS" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS_MAGIC_MISSILE" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS_SHIELD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Burning Hands" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS_BURNING_HANDS">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>Your backhand slap is legendary. As an action, you can make an Unarmed Strike against each creature within your reach. On a hit, this strike deals Bludgeoning damage equal to 1d8 plus your Strength modifier and the target has Disadvantage on the next attack it makes before the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Rage - 1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can make an Unarmed Strike against each creature within your reach. On a hit, this strike deals 1d8+{{strength:modifier}} Bludgeoning damage and the target has Disadvantage on the next attack it makes before the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Magic Missile" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS_MAGIC_MISSILE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>As an action, you can make three ranged attacks using Darts, Daggers, or other weapons with Thrown that use Strength for the attack and damage rolls. Because Magic Missile never misses, you have Advantage on these attack rolls.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action" usage="Rage - 1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can make three ranged attacks using weapons with Thrown that use Strength for the attack and damage rolls. You have Advantage on these attack rolls.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_SPELLS_SHIELD">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<description>
			<p>When you are hit by an attack roll, you can take a Reaction to quickly don a Shield to defend yourself. You gain the Shield's AC bonus against the triggering attack, potentially causing it to miss. If the attack hits, the damage dealt to you is reduced by an amount equal to your Barbarian level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction" usage="Rage - 1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you are hit by an attack roll, you can quickly don a Shield to defend yourself. You gain the Shield's AC bonus against the triggering attack, potentially causing it to miss. If the attack hits, the damage dealt to you is reduced by {{level:barbarian}}.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 10: Magic Resistance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_MAGIC_RESISTANCE">
		<description>
			<p>You're such an amazing wizard that other wizards can't even touch you. While your Rage is active, you have Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Magic Resistance" usage="Rage">
			<description>While your Rage is active, you have Advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Level 14: I Cast Fist" type="Archetype Feature" source="Valda's Spire of Secrets: Player Pack" id="ID_MHP_VSSPP_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARBARIAN_MUSCLE_WIZARD_I_CAST_FIST">
		<description>
			<p>You can crush your enemies with your ultimate "spell":</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Fist.</i></b> When you take the Attack action while your Rage is active, you can replace one of your attacks with a really hard punch. Make an Unarmed Strike with Advantage. On a hit, the target takes Bludgeoning damage equal to 6d6 plus your Strength modifier and has the Prone condition if it is Huge or smaller. You can use this feature once per active Rage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="I Cast Fist" action="Attack Action" usage="1/Active Rage">
			<description>While your Rage is active, you can replace one of your attacks with a really hard punch. Make an Unarmed Strike with Advantage. On a hit, the target takes Bludgeoning damage equal to 6d6+{{strength:modifier}} and has the Prone condition if it is Huge or smaller.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

</elements>
